[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Welcome Living Mana Church family. We
are so happy that you are worshiping
with us today. We are happy to be here
with you live and back from down under
literally
>> from And so we're so happy to be with
you guys.
>> Still catching up to
>> Still catching up with our sleep. I Yes.
I was just thinking like we used to be
able to travel the world, come back and
just bounce back like one day.
>> Yeah. Not anymore.
>> Not anymore. But we're happy to see you
guys. so happy that you've decided to
worship with us here at Living Mana
Church. We are excited that it's the
Sabbath. Um that we're just going to
talk about the goodness of God and just
to hear just what the Lord has for us
today on this Sabbath day where we get
to just rest, which is such a blessing.
Please put in the chat where you are
viewing from. And if this is your very
first time with Living Mana Church, put
a one in the chat. We want to say a very
special welcome to you.
>> Yeah, we uh we're as she just said, we
are coming back from Australia. We were
there for a week,
>> a little week and a half
>> speaking uh at uh the Dundes 7th Day
Adventist Church. Dundas 7th Day
Adventist Church.
>> Um and uh uh Pastor Lami,
>> yes,
>> covered for us last week. And so um that
was a blessing
he was able to able to share and um
>> yes
>> you know we're glad to be back.
>> We're glad to be back.
>> We are tired.
>> Yes we are tired and we had a very
amazing time there in Australia with the
wonderful people there. It was a
blessing and uh they watch Living Man of
Church. So that was h that was exciting
to get to meet some of the um viewership
um in Australia. All right. I am missing
places here. Let's say let's see. We
have hap let's see. Happy Sabbath um to
Terrence in New York City. Welcome to
Living Mana Church. All right. Yes.
Happy Sabbath to you, Keith. And yes,
they say good day. Good day, mate. Good
day. Um All right. And we have Jen. Um
uh Jen watching from Tennessee. Welcome
to Living Mana Church. Veronica from
Washington State. Good to see you. Very
good to see you. Welcome. Welcome.
Welcome. All right. And we have MNA from
Tacoma, Washington.
>> Terry Parker from Lacy, Washington. Got
a lot of Washington people today.
Welcome here to Living Man Church. I
believe Jerry from Rochester, New York.
Welcome. Jody, our one and our our our
member, our board member from the
beautiful island. I always say of
Vancouver Island. You would have thought
I've I've been there because I always
say the beautiful island, but that's
what I've heard of it. So, I believe
that it is beautiful. Um, yes. Welcome
from Yukon, Oklahoma. Welcome here to
Living Mana Church, Greenville, North
Carolina. Laura from Greenville,
welcome. So happy to see you guys here.
>> And I see Jamaica.
>> Okay. Yeah, Jamaica. your your home
country. Welcome. Always good to see you
here at Living Mana Church. There's
popping up. All right, we have Sirill
from South of France. Welcome. I've
heard south of France is very beautiful,
too. Another place I've never seen. Not
the south of France.
>> Um I heard it's a lot like Italy,
though.
>> I heard I heard it looks like a lot like
Italy. So, welcome here to Living Man
Church. Um, and welcome to
uh, okay, Mary'sville, Washington. We've
driven through Mary'sville. I remember
we've driven through Mary'sville,
Washington. Welcome. Another person from
Washington. We have Atlanta. OKC. It's
wonderful to see all of you here today.
Welcome here to Living Mana Church.
>> And your chat is visible. Is visible uh,
Rain. So, we see you.
>> Yep, we see you.
>> You are here. So, um, we got a good
Sabbath school.
>> Yes.
>> In store today. I know we have some
transfers.
>> We do. We have some transfers, which is
always exciting.
>> And we're going to be continuing our,
uh, our, uh, study on the Christian art
of war. Yes.
>> Specifically, the fruit of the spirit.
So, um, we have our guest back with us.
We're going to be picking up on that,
>> uh, after we do these, uh, memberships.
>> Yes. And uh I believe that God's going
to bless us uh again tremendously as he
has been.
>> Amen. Um okay. So this is the second
reading for Sylvia Alvarodo. Alvaredo,
sorry. Alvaredo Ortega from South St.
Paul Hispanic 7th Day Adventist Church.
>> All right. So and that's the only second
reading.
>> Second reading. Okay. Now let me do the
first reading. So I'll do the first
reading. So we have two first readings.
This is for Thomas Harris. He is
transferring from Oakwood University
Church. And the second one is Elina
Rodriguez Ruez from the Marina Spanish
7th Day Adventist Church. So those are
the first readings for Thomas and Elina.
And it's the second reading for Sylvia
Alvarodto. Alvaredo, sorry. Ortega.
>> Yeah. And uh Thomas, if you are
watching, you know I've been waiting
looking for your transfer. So um Thomas
is actually um a parent of one of the
students that I taught
>> at the academy. Wonderful.
>> Um one of my best students.
>> Okay.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes.
>> This is this is the father of one of the
best students. Okay. That's amazing.
>> So um but anyway, we're going to uh go
ahead and um do a vote for Sister
Sylvia.
>> Yes. Is that Kathy?
>> Yep. And so, uh, let's go ahead. Uh, we
need a motion, uh, and then we need a
second and then we're going to go ahead
and, uh, go through with the votes. So,
uh, do we have a motion?
I know there's a little, uh, delay. So,
>> yes.
>> Uh,
>> yes, we got a motion.
>> All right. So, we got a motion to
accept. Um, and uh I'm going to take
Ramona as a second
and then we'll go ahead and uh open the
floor for our members uh to vote Sister
Sylvia in to become an official member
of the Living Mana uh online church. So,
let us put a one in the chat.
>> Yep. One in the chat to uh uh accept
Sister Sylvia into uh fellowship.
And the ones begin to come in.
>> Amen. Amen. So beautiful to see all the
ones
and just so beautiful to always be
welcoming a new church member into our
church officially.
>> Officially
>> because even if you're in a a viewing
audience that comes all the time, we're
all you are a part of our church family.
And so we are thankful for you and this
is official church membership. So we are
excited about that.
>> Amen. Amen.
All right. It is it is done. Welcome
Sylvia.
>> Yes.
>> To the living online family.
>> We are excited for you to get involved
in every way that you feel the Lord is
leading you. uh what you would like to
do. Um in like we don't just come to the
church and be served, but we also just
go out to do service, you know, to
others and just, you know, the blessing
that you can be here at Living Man
Church. So, we're excited to see uh how
God is going to be leading you in your
service. We're excited to have you.
Welcome.
>> Amen. Amen. Yeah. Y'all welcome her in
the chat. Amen.
>> Yes. All right. While they are doing
that,
>> like to do the t-shirt message.
>> Uh, pray, wait, trust God has a plan.
>> Yes. And um
I think I shared this the last time we
were here two weeks ago. I believe that,
you know, I'd been praying about
something and God was, you know, really
showing us or showing me and just that,
you know, he was answering that prayer
that he was making big moves um in that
situation and, you know, I was just
excited about it. And then I'm still
very excited about it because I still
see how he is moving and answering that
prayer. Um, and then I was thinking
about um this shirt. It's like, you
know, just pray, trust, he has a plan.
And it's not always easy that trust part
when we're praying. But you know our
topic today, the fruit of the spirit. I
believe we're talking about uh joy.
>> It's like I was thinking about that we
need to have joy with that trust.
>> Yeah.
>> While we're trusting, we need to have
joy. And I learned that or it was really
like introduced to me in a serious way
was uh through a prayer mentor of mine,
Janet Paige. She, you know, before we
had the answer to the prayer, she would
always just say, she like, "Praise the
Lord. Praise him now. Praise him now."
She always would encourage me to do
that.
>> Um, and I can see why because that keeps
your spirits at a good, healthy level in
that trust space.
>> Yeah.
>> Because we can pray and then just be so
down and um even low-key depressed
because, you know, we don't know if the
answer's coming or where it's at and all
of those things. But if we praise him
during that time in that space of trust,
>> we will have peace in this journey.
>> So always pray, trust he has a plan.
Believe that the when we're praying
within his will, we can have all the
confidence that the prayer is going to
be answered.
>> Amen. Which is a very good segue
into
our
>> joy. Sabbath school.
>> Sabbath school.
>> Amen.
>> Joy. Amen.
>> Joy,
>> joy.
>> So, uh, we're going to go ahead and
invite our guests on.
>> Yes. We're gonna invite our guest
>> and, um,
we covered we're in the fruit of the
spirit. Um, in the book, The Christian
Art of War,
>> uh, we've covered, uh, love. Yes,
>> we first talked about the mighty men
>> before you because I want to just point
out that the book you guys, the book is
the Christian Art of War. Please in
mighty networks. That's where you can
get the chapters one, two, three, and
four. We're releasing them as we go
through them. So, ple I pray that over
these last two weeks, you guys have been
reading and studying on your own, but
it's in the chat now. So, I just didn't
want to miss that opportunity to let you
guys know that. Please get the book so
you can study and and dialogue with us.
Please be putting in the chat your
thoughts and comments as well. Yeah,
>> go ahead.
>> And um Mark, I see your comment. Just uh
reach out to Patrice at living
mana.urch.
>> Yes. And I'll talk about that in the
divine worship service. Yes. Yes. Mark.
>> Um okay. So, um
we covered the fruit of love.
>> We're about to get into the to the fruit
of uh joy.
>> Yes. So, let's get our guests on. This
is chapter four, everyone. Chapter four,
>> was amazing. I can still remember um
anyway.
>> Yep.
>> All the love stuff that we talked about,
and that was amazing.
>> Yep.
>> So, joy is going to be no different. So,
while they're coming on, we should pray.
>> Yeah. Let's pray. Heavenly Father, thank
you, Lord, for um
your amazing grace. Thank you for just
giving us the opportunity, Lord, to
worship you today, Lord. and we are
gathered from different parts of the
world today um coming to hear a word
from you Lord. And so as we um get into
the Sabbath school, Lord, I pray that
you would speak to our hearts, Lord. Um
just uh grant us the fruit of the
spirit. That is our prayer today. We ask
it in Jesus name. Be with our guests as
we share. We ask this in Jesus name.
Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
All right, there they are. Yes, our
guest. Kazia from Tanzania. Great to see
you. Welcome always. Brother Terry, I
know you can only be with us for a short
time, but we're happy that you're here
this morning. And Melinda, we missed you
from a couple weeks ago. Welcome back.
Great to have all three of you here
today. We are so excited for you to
share this conversation with us in this
study I should say about joy, one of the
fruits of the spirit. So
with that said, do you guys you know
what? I'm going to definitely let
brother Terry go first because I know
he's on a time constraint, so he won't
be with us our whole conversation. So
>> Terry,
happy Sabbath.
We I can't we can't hear you actually.
Um, so we'll just have to let our um
studio engineers know that we cannot
hear um our guest and we'll work on
that.
But I see your studio. Uh, we're we're m
we're twinning today, Terry. Our
backgrounds are twinning. That's great.
We're in unity.
It looks really good. It looks really
good. So, while they work on that,
because we definitely, and I don't know
if it's just us in the studio, put a one
in the chat if our um viewing audience
can hear our guest. If you can hear our
guest, guest say happy Sabbath so we can
see if this the the uh viewing audience
can hear you.
Okay. So, it looks like
>> Yeah. So, I know our Okay. I know our
engineers are working on it. So,
>> we'll go ahead and start.
>> Yes.
>> And um we'll just uh you know, wait to
see if our guests are going to be able
to come on,
>> right?
>> Um I'm praying they can't.
>> Yeah.
>> So, let's start with the joy of war. I'm
going to go ahead and read this first
paragraph. And it says, "We we struggle
to do what is a burden. We love to do
what is a joy." We could just stop right
there. We could just Yeah,
>> we really could just stop right there.
>> That's the joy of of war.
>> I mean, it just goes so well with what I
was talking about. Wow.
>> Um, when something is a burden,
>> you don't it's a struggle to do it.
>> And for a lot of people, I think the
Christian walk instead of being a joy,
>> it's a burden. And when it's a burden,
>> you get miserable.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Nobody likes burdens.
>> No.
>> Right. Right.
>> Um we um I was sharing with someone uh a
couple of days ago that
when something is your hobby.
>> It was a Bible study class. It was in
Australia. We're talking about Bible
study.
>> We were talking about you did say that.
And uh we were sharing that I was
sharing that you know a lot of people
look at Bible study as a chore
>> right
>> and when it's a chore it's not something
that you really enjoy
>> doing. You're just like I I have to
study my Bible so let me get it over
with.
>> And so my appeal was make Bible study
your hobby.
>> Yes.
>> Because when it's a hobby
>> then you get Yeah.
>> you enjoy
>> doing it.
And so I think the same principle is
true here, right? Um
are we enjoying
our Christian walk?
>> Um are we
are we just to let y'all know we do hear
>> We do. I just heard I just heard a
voice. I think I heard Kazia or Melinda.
I heard I heard one of them.
>> Yeah.
>> So we can hear you.
>> So
um
the Yeah. our Christian walk.
The Christian walk for a lot of people
is a burden.
>> Yes.
>> Um
I remember um I don't know if anybody
has ever put a one in the chat if you've
ever listened to or read the book um the
the um Pilgrim's Journey.
>> Pilgrim's Progress Pilgrim's Progress.
>> You know, I've never really read it, but
because our kids listen, they used to
listen to it on audio tape. all the
time.
>> So, and even there was a board game to
show the journey. So, I know it, but I
haven't read it.
>> And so,
>> I mean, all the time. You're right. I
listen to it.
>> Yeah. So, in the book, uh, this is, by
the way, this is page
Oh, boy. I got the wrong page. Um,
>> cuz I I have a PDF format and it says
page five, but this is not page five in
the book. Um, but we are on the chap.
It's chapter four, the Christian art of
war, and it's the very we started with
love and now we're on joy.
>> Um, so in The Pilgrim's Progress,
>> um,
the the main character's name is
Christian.
>> And the the story starts out with
Christian carrying a burden.
>> Yes. and all he does like the whole
first part of that Pilgrim's Progress
it's you know woe is me. I was just
going to say I remember that like just
like oh this is so
>> everything was a burden everything was
just
>> everything was a burden
>> and when he gets to the cross
>> the burden he's carrying the burden like
it's a book bag like a bag on his back
sack right
>> and when he gets to the cross he drops
the burden
>> yes
>> and joy takes over
>> so you cannot both have burden and joy
at the same time
>> they don't mix into space.
>> You have to drop one
to embrace the other.
>> I love that as a therapist. Wow. I'm
just thinking
how I'm going to present that to my
clients. But yes, it's very good. I want
to let Terry co because I know his time
is limited and because of the sound he
wasn't able to talk. So, Brother Terry,
>> hello.
>> Hi. Happy Sabbath.
>> Hi. Happy Sabbath. And do you do you
want to pick up on you know did you hear
what we were sharing about joy?
>> What pastor?
>> Yes I did.
>> Okay. Yes. Please.
>> I have I have a bit of my own joy this
morning. Jo I'm I'm rejoicing over
seeing you guys again.
>> Yeah. You too. We missed you too.
>> And and and then there was a little bit
of love in there too because uh I just
couldn't I just couldn't get on the road
without seeing y'all. So I love y'all so
much. And Belinda Kia. Good seeing
y'all. Living man of family. love y'all.
Uh yeah, you know, you were talking
about joy. You know, for me, joy is
related a lot to um like I mean, you
just you can't fake genuine joy, right?
If it's real, it's there. And I I thank
God, you know, with everything that's
happened in my life and, you know, um
all the tragedy and all the heartache
and stuff I have had to go through and
then to see and know that God actually
loves me and cares for me and has a plan
and purpose for my life that produces a
joy like nothing else. I mean, I could
even begin to, you know, come up with on
my own. So, uh, I'm I'm rejoicing at
just having the opportunity to be able
to serve, to have a family like you
guys, and, uh, to be a part of the body
of Christ. I mean, my joy is just
overflowing. I got a lot of reasons to
be rejoicing, but, um, I love what
pastor said about, you know, the joy of
studying the word of God. Um, you know,
when I when I first started, you know,
realizing that just personal God's
actually talking to me and he began to
confirm his promises, that made studying
the word of God really a joy because
what's he going to say next? What's he
going to reveal next? And I know
everybody who watches Living Man has got
to be like, "Wow, what is God gonna say
next to this pastor?" You know, so we're
we're excited. We're rejoicing because
with everything that's going on in the
world, you know, the world's getting
darker. Uh so so much is going on
that's, you know, could be distracting
and heartbreaking and God has given us
this awesome word week after week after
week, day after day. And the tools he's
given us to learn how to study his word.
We have a lot to rejoice about.
>> Amen.
>> And uh so yeah, just my first initial
thoughts and
>> Amen.
>> I have another joy. We're not leaving as
soon as I thought we were according to
>> uh Sister Ammer. So, all right.
>> Well, good. All right. Good. Then we
have you a little bit longer. That's
great. That brings me joy.
>> Okay. Yeah. Belinda and Kazilla, do you
have anything that you would like to
share?
>> And guys, you can feel you can feel free
to jump to jump ahead. Yeah.
>> If there's something else in, you know,
whatever with joy that you're like, "Oh,
this really jumped out to me." Feel free
to to to jump ahead. I'll keep reading
as as usual, but you know, don't feel
stuck on what I just said.
>> So, something that kind of um
with the first sentence, we struggle to
do what is a burden. We love to do what
is a joy. Um what jumps out to me on
that is how Jesus says, "Come to me all
you who are weary and are heavy laden,
and I'll give you le uh rest." And I
think
that that burden of weariness and the
burden of heavy labor
is the burden of a carnal walk with God.
>> And
Jesus says, "Come to me." And when we
come to him and we spend time in his
presence, we become like him. We get
restored.
I'm sorry, but the past week I was
studying about Christ's nature and
Adam's nature. And when we spend time
with Christ, we become back to Adam's
nature. We become sons and daughters of
God just like he was. Mhm.
>> And that burden of, oh, keeping the
commandments out of my own power or out
of my own grit,
>> um, it goes away because now you're
keeping them out of joy
>> in the response of the love Jesus showed
you.
>> I don't know if that makes sense.
>> It makes complete sense, Melinda. Thank
you. It's so beautiful to hear a
>> a 17year-old say, "Yeah, I was studying
this week." Okay, but go ahead. It's
beautiful.
Yeah,
>> I can also see
um
I don't know, it's just just knowing
that we have to have joy in um doing
um the just being able to be the devil
having joy. It seems hard to me because
uh you know it isn't easy to go against
temptation and um just know just having
to get that art of war or to perfect
that combination is um it's it's
difficult but through God's help I
believe that all of us can have a joy to
go against.
>> Yeah. I mean, I like what I want to
piggyback off what you said, Kazia. Um,
how it's difficult to resist temptation
and a lot of times it it's absolutely
impossible. Actually, like it's
realistically impossible. But then we
get the assurance where Jesus says with
man all things are possible. Well, with
Christ everything is possible. And we
have where Paul says um if any man be in
Christ, he is a new creation. So the old
man is gone and the new is here. And now
suddenly we're doing this in Christ's
power with Christ possessing us. So it's
not impossible anymore. It is perfectly
doable. And I I just love a practical
gospel like that. I I don't know.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen.
Absolutely beautiful.
I think uh
you know you're you had brought up um
the nature of Adam and the nature of
Christ and um you know I think a lot of
times we in our church we get into
arguments over what nature
>> Jesus had and I think we miss the entire
point
>> that
the point is that we need the nature of
Christ.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> And you know, well, what n I mean, I
I've I've got my position on what nature
he had, but
>> regardless of that,
>> the most important thing is that we must
have the nature of Christ.
>> And we can have the nature of Christ.
That's what Christianity is.
>> It means to be Christlike,
to be like him in nature. for our
nature. We are getting rid of our our
nature and taking on his nature.
>> And his nature is super.
>> Yeah.
>> So that means that you know when we have
a our nature is
>> is normal
>> natural his nature
>> is super it is supernatural.
>> Amen. And the Christian life
>> is about
attaining that supernatural nature.
>> And
you know, I think it's important we look
back looking back at Adam and Eve, they
lost their joy
>> when when sin entered.
>> And I think a lot of
>> they lost their love too.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> Because perfect love casteth out fear
and they hid out of from God in fear.
>> Yeah.
>> Which is which is kind of crazy when you
think about it. In eating the fruit,
they lost the fruit.
>> Yes.
>> In eating the fruit of
>> Wow. Okay.
>> They lost the fruit of the spirit.
>> Yeah. And I think that lesson is very
>> very important for us to understand
because
when we eat that when we eat forbidden
fruit,
>> it takes away our joy, our peace, it
takes everything away.
>> Um
>> Amen.
>> And that joy,
Satan's way of attacking joy, of
stealing joy. In fact, in Nehemiah 8:10,
the Bible says, "The joy of the Lord is
your strength."
>> So, if the joy of the Lord is our
strength, then Satan knows, man, if I I
got to take joy away from them so that
they become weak.
>> Amen.
>> And
how many of us does he successfully do
that with? You know what I'm saying?
>> So, when we start talking about, well,
how can I practice joy? Um,
we talked about uh proactive
righteousness and reactive
righteousness,
>> offensive righteousness and defensive
righteousness.
>> So, I think the question for us is in
what ways, remember when you're
practicing defense, that's that's not in
your right in your power. You don't know
when someone's going to come at you as
we keep saying sideways.
>> And then you have to respond with joy.
>> But we can take the initiative and walk
in joy in that positive sense, right?
Positive righteousness, active
righteousness. So how does that happen?
>> Like Lord, teach me how to
>> teach me how to praise you. Because
that's what praise is. Praise
>> praise is actually the act of joy.
Amen.
>> So when we're praising God,
>> uh you get this idea of you're joyous,
right? You're like happy. You're like,
"Yes, I'm
>> even even in
>> not when everything around you is
joyous, but when you praise and well,
it's going to connect to what I wanted
to say, but when you praise even in that
time, um that's how you have joy."
>> Yeah.
>> Even when the situation around you is
not a joyous situation. Yeah. So, I can
say this and I know I think someone
wanted to jump in and add something, but
I'm going to say this real quick is that
I think joy is a
is a
time
>> and it's a choice too.
>> Yeah,
>> it's a choice.
>> But it's a time it is strengthened with
time,
>> right? So, that means
in the downtime, oh, nothing bad's
happening in my life, man. Let me let me
start building joy now so that when that
thing comes, when that moment comes
that's going to test my joy, I've built
up joy strength.
>> Yeah, you have a full bank of joy,
>> right? I got a full bank of joy. So
something's hit and okay, I have I have
enough joy. I've been training in joy
for so long
>> that when this thing hits, my joy isn't
broken down.
>> Oh man, there's a statement that just
came to mind. Mhm.
>> Um
it's a statement where where uh
the statement goes something like some
of us have so um so small or so weak an
atmosphere or a or a shield of
>> I don't know if it was faith or joy but
it goes on to say that Satan often
succeeds breaks the barrier on his first
try.
because of the lack of joy
>> because of the lack of or the the
weakness of the fruit of the spirit
around us.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> So
the idea is we have to build these
things right
>> when in the time of the footmen so that
when the horses come
>> we have that strength.
>> Amen.
>> Go ahead.
>> Amen. Yeah pastor. Um, I like what you
and you and Melinda were talking about
having that nature, that likeness of
Christ. And so the Bible tells us that
we already partake of the divine nature,
right? So we know we have that already.
We've got a reason to rejoice already.
We enjoy being a fruit of the spirit is
a natural outflow of that that nature we
have. You all right? So we have
something really more than anyone else
to rejoice about and that is we are
partakers of the divine nature of
Christ. But this this verse here in
Hebrews
12:e 2 we all know says looking unto
Jesus the author and finisher of our
faith who for the joy that set before
him endured the cross to despising the
shame sat down at the right hand of the
throne of God. And I I believe for me
and I and I maybe a lot of us will agree
that if I could just discipline myself,
train myself even in the downtime when
things aren't happening bad or
challenging which is hardly ever. It's
always a challenge and a temptation in
in this life. But if I can train myself
to stay focused and you know by
beholding we become if I can keep my
eyes on that prize.
>> So my discipline for me is Lord help me
because so much is going on in the world
around me. help me stay focused on this
reason to rejoice. And as a result, as
I'm looking at it, the natural outflow
of that is just going to be joy. I mean,
>> I might have joy in some situation where
folk actually think I'm crazy, but what
are you so rejoicing about? All this
stuff going on around, but joy is that
supernatural thing that it doesn't make
sense. That's that crazy peace.
Philippians is talking about, you know,
that that that the peace of God which
surpasses all understanding will guard
your hearts and mind. That is the
outflow of joy I want out of my life.
You know that I don't need to feel like
I gotta work it up. I don't feel like I
gotta pump it up because doing that
after a while and you're going to get
tired of that, right?
>> You know, it's going to wear off. But
that natural supernatural joy that flows
out of that divine nature we all as
believers, true believers partake of.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen. And that's what I meant when
I said it's a choice. It's not it's not
hard to choose joy when it's like
automatic when good things are good.
you're just like, "Oh, I'm so excited
naturally because everything is good and
but it's a choice when things are going
badly or, you know, it's a choice to um
choose joy and it's basically like
you're in a situation and you're
choosing joy and you can pivot to just
because because of your faith in God and
because it's almost like
>> to have because I was thinking like you
know to have true uh joy we have to
believe in God espec we have to have
true faith because in that time where
things are not going well u it's almost
imposs if you don't have true faith it's
almost impossible to choose joy because
you have it's like you have joy because
you know who God is like okay I I have
joy because and I can smile and I'm
excited almost like you're
>> watching watching a movie if you will
like because you know that you have the
power most powerful thing in the
universe on your side and you have faith
and you guys have a relationship and
this is this journey that you guys are
on and so you could be like okay God I
have joy I'm excited what are you going
to do next how are you going to do this
how are you going to you know work this
out you have joy because of him
>> yeah um
>> let me let me and who he is yeah I'm
going to add to that that um I I think
you just said something about, you know,
it's easy to be happy when good things
happen.
>> And I think for a lot of us,
our joy is based on good things
happening.
>> Right.
>> Right. So if something good happens,
then I'm happy.
>> Right. I'm reser I reserve my joy for
when good things happen. And if that is
the source of my joy when good things
happen then it makes sense that when bad
things happen yeah uh you know my joy
goes away and
I don't have that joy anymore because my
joy is based on
>> did anything
>> it's situational
>> yeah it's situation
situational joy
>> situational joy
>> okay so I just want to
>> what God calls us
>> I just want to um
>> sorry I I don't want to interrupt, but I
was just thinking about
>> what you said, pastor. Um, that is true.
Like a lot of times our joy is based on
>> situations,
>> situational things like, oh, if good
things happen equals me having joy.
>> But I'm wondering if that is a side
effect of where our focus is.
>> Because in I think it's Colossians, um,
Paul writes that set your mind on things
above, not on things that are on this
earth. And when our thing when our mind
is focused on the things that are around
us and things around us physically are
are okay and they're going great and
good things are happening then we're
going to be joyful. Of course that's
>> the reaction of
>> natural. Exactly. But when our minds are
focused on things above that focus is
now Jesus. And the good thing that
happened in that realm, in that focus,
is he came and delivered me from sin.
>> Mhm.
>> Therefore, I am now a son slash whatever
a daughter of God, you know.
>> Um, and I think it depends on where your
focus is.
>> Yeah.
>> Are you going to have situational joy
based on um your earthly things or are
you going to have situational joy based
heavenly things? Yeah.
>> Uh unconditional joy.
>> So I think a lot of us have conditional
joy.
>> Yeah.
>> And a conditional joy is did something
good happen?
>> Will something good happen today? And
it's in the earthly realm.
>> Situational joy is is easy.
>> Is easy
>> because it takes no faith,
>> right?
>> Because you can see it. Oh, this is
happening. Of course, I'm happy. Mhm.
If
>> you know that that that's that's exactly
what Habac was saying in Habac 3:17.
Believe pastor, you were just saying you
had to have faith. And she he says,
"Although the fig tree shall not
blossom, neither shall fruit be in the
vines, the labor of the olive shall
fail, the field shall yield no meat, the
flock shall be cut off from the fo,
there shall be no herd in the soul. Yet
will I rejoice in the Lord. I will joy
in the God of my salvation."
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, he's saying, "These things could be
going bad, but I'm still rejoicing in
the Lord."
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> That's where my focus is.
>> Yeah. I'm looking at what Janice just
said. Uh Janice Ferguson said, "I don't
think there there is anything wrong in
being sad when a loved one dies as Jesus
wept when when Lazarus died." God gave
us these emotions as humans as long as
we don't wallow too long in sadness, you
know, wallow too long in sadness. And I
think that is uh
that is a very powerful point
>> and that Paul addresses that.
>> He even says even in death that we
should not sorrow
>> as others sorrow
>> as the
>> as the world sorrows. Right?
>> Why? Because we actually have the joy
that
um
we have the joy of an eternal life,
>> right? We have the joy of you know
seeing that loved one again. We have the
joy of knowing that we will live again
by the grace of God. So
>> that is the biggest blessing I believe
that God gave us.
>> And it's so sad that
the world does not understand that
blessing the way they need to understand
it. meaning
going to I mean of course you go to I'm
sorry and I didn't mean to cut you off
but
you know going to a funeral and they
either put the people right in heaven
right now or type of thing but um or
they just don't have any understanding
that Jesus you know is coming to get us
and we can live again truly
>> um you know not having that
understanding or thinking you'll never
see that person again that is p you know
very sad, very devastating, but God is
saying, you know, of you know that you
will live again.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and you can see your loved ones
again, those who, you know, die in
Christ.
>> Yeah. Um Veronica just asked, "Is it
possible to have joy
>> and still be who is
>> That was Kazia or Melinda's."
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Okay.
>> All right. I'll read this. I'm gonna
answer this real quick then then jump
in. Okay. Uh, is it possible to have joy
and still be in intense emotional pain?
And I think the answer is yes.
>> Yes, I think so.
>> Yeah. Yes. Absolutely.
>> Because Jesus was a man of sorrow.
>> That's right. He was a man of sorrow.
Watch. He was a man of sorrow and yet
for the joy that was set before him.
>> Exactly.
>> Wait. Exactly.
>> As the queen interrupter, I'm going to
like let I want I want to let Kazia I'm
gonna interrupt both of you and Melinda
to let Kazia go.
Go because yeah, go ahead.
>> I was gonna say
I was gonna say something similar if not
okay. Um I just say the thing of the joy
of winning
and um it has so much to do with yeah we
have to get used to the divine nature of
the joy of winning and not our human
nature where we win something and we
just go exactly erupting and oh my word
oh I won blah blah blah. But uh we have
to also have that in our way of actually
in divine nature when we win a battle
with the devil because we find sometimes
when we fight with the devil afterwards
you're like oh my word I'm just totally
drained you know God I'm done
>> but instead of having that kind of
attitude toward it we should be like oh
my word I won I beat the devil and it
should be that way instead of constantly
having a sour attitude. And what you
said about emotional pain, it's so true.
We can have emotional pain
>> when when we've won.
>> You can be like, "Oh my word, what did
I, you know, just do."
>> And um when having the joy, it helps us.
It really helps us. That's what I was
gonna say.
>> Yeah.
>> And Yes. Amen. Amen. Having having Jesus
is really
that joy. I mean, having him in your
heart
>> and is how we have not we're not talking
about the situational joy, but the re I
don't want to say the real well, yeah,
I'll say it. The real joy because the
real joy from him is not based on
situations. It's, you know, that his the
it's just the being of who Jesus is and
how he um affects us in our lives, the
way he is there for us all the time.
Like he loves us so much that it's
almost like to have a real relationship
with him, it's almost impossible not to
have joy back because you're with this
God who loves you so much. He's so
personable. He's there for your every
need. It's just almost like a the way a
marriage should be. You know what I
mean? your your your husband or wife
should be loving, kind, and you know,
there for you and to support you. Jesus
is all of those things and more. And so,
it's easy to be joyful.
Um, even in a in a marriage when your
spouse treats you the way that you
should be treated, like you want to do
nice things for them and you want to
speak kindly to them. And I'm just using
that as an example of, you know, when
Jesus is Jesus is always that to us.
Yeah.
>> And so our natural response is going to
be when we have a when we're in a
relationship with him is to have joy.
>> Yeah.
>> And not not situational joy, but real
joy.
>> Yep. Um,
how is Jesus a man of sorrow
and yet for the joy that was set before
him, he endures everything.
I think uh
it is
that's an important distinction.
Um,
I was looking in the comments and I see
Zadena said that she lost her brother
and has been struggling with that.
>> I'm sorry.
>> And you know, I'll tell you, uh, Sister
Zadina, that losing my brother has been
the worst thing I've experienced. Um, at
least thus far. It has
it
it it I don't even have words coming out
right now to to to to explain
>> um you know how much it has affected me.
>> Yeah.
>> And
yet that joy that he had
>> Yeah.
>> as he was going through his trial just
>> was absolutely stunning.
And
you know, watching someone go through
these sorrows while holding holding on
to joy um
is a ve very powerful thing.
>> Yeah. And so even though
>> still speaks to us to this day
>> and even though I'm still, you know, I
don't uh I have not
gotten over and will probably never get
over the loss of my brother.
>> It's not something that that I'm going
to get over and I know that.
>> But
the
the peace of God has kept me.
>> Amen. You know, the joy of the Lord has
kept me uh even through this.
>> Yeah, he has.
>> Uh and listen, it's not a joy of me
like, "Oh, hey. Yeah, so what my
brother." No,
>> no.
>> It's a different type of,
>> you know, and I've said this before,
like
the Bible study is my hobby,
>> right?
>> My release, my
um
joy. Mhm.
>> is
ministering to people, preaching the
word of God, watching people come to
life, watching people, you know, leave
the lifestyle of darkness to to come
into life. So that's like, okay, you
know, when you have that thing that
you're like, I'm stressed. What do I
need to do?
>> Do something you enjoy.
>> Yeah.
that thing that we should enjoy doing is
the Christian walk,
>> is witnessing, is sharing,
>> is letting our light shine.
>> And
I just think that's important to
understand because it it helps us to
know, yes, we can be people of sorrow,
>> but even in the midst of the sorrow,
>> we can also have joy,
>> right?
>> That's different from burdens. Mhm.
>> Sorrows are to be expected.
>> But God doesn't call us, right? He says,
"Let me bear your burdens."
>> Amen.
>> Come unto me all you that labor and a
heavy laden and I will give you rest.
Right? I'll take your burden.
>> Take it.
>> The burden gone doesn't mean that you
don't suffer sorrow, right? That you
don't experience sorrow,
>> but you're able to experience sorrow on
the cross. Jesus was both a man of
sorrow
while having the joy that was set before
him. And it was the joy that was set
before him that enabled him to endure
the sorrow.
>> What he he knew what he was doing for
us.
>> And though there was sorrow there, there
was joy because of what he was doing for
us. Which takes us back to, and I think
Huzzah said it in the last one we were
talking about love, or maybe Melinda
said it, I don't know which one of them
said it.
That love is still that first that
foundational fruit of the spirit.
>> Yeah.
>> Because he had joy because he loved us
that much.
>> And saying, "Yes, this is painful."
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. What I'm going through right now is
difficult. I even feel like I'm
separated from my father, but I know
what I'm doing by faith is going to save
the world.
>> Yeah. So for the joy that was set before
him, he endured.
>> He endured
>> the suffering, the sorrow, the cross,
the pain.
>> Yes.
>> Without joy, without that joy, what was
the joy set before him? He saw the
future.
>> Yeah. He saw the future.
>> So our joy then
should be based upon seeing the future.
>> And that's where he
>> and that's where faith comes in. Yes.
>> Because if we don't have faith, we can't
see the future.
>> And that's where
He literally was he it's not like Jesus
didn't have to do what we have to do. He
had to have faith that all that was
still going to happen. You know what I'm
saying? Like you know we have faith in
in him even when we we sorrow. But um he
he had to do that and because he walked
that walk we can do it too. Like he
experienced all that for us. Like he
literally had to have faith.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> To stay up on that cross. Yeah.
>> Like, okay. And because he knew the
character of his father.
>> Um, yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Don't we have guests somewhere?
>> We do have guests. We do have guests.
Where are they? Have they left us? Come
back.
>> Come back.
>> We haven't left.
>> I don't know. This
>> We hear you, but we don't see you on the
stage.
>> We do hear you. This concept of joy is
just so
it's just so beautiful. It's just so
beautiful. I don't know when you were
talking and I know guys I've been
talking I don't know look because
I don't like I don't want to talk about
this so much like I because I don't it's
not a anyways this is it's a personal
thing between me and God but I just want
to say my experience with fasting is
almost like it's not what Jesus
experienced but you're denying self like
you're sorrowing because you want to eat
you know it's do you understand what I'm
saying but you're if you're fasting and
praying like the Bible tells us that for
you know we need to fast and pray over,
you know, certain things. And
when you're going through that sorrow or
lo loss of food or nutrition at that
moment and you're hungry and you're
having those hunger pains, like you're
you're just you're going through pain
and you're having faith because you're
praying whatever you're praying for for
the will of God that God is going to do
what he has to do. And I just feel like
that's in a much smaller way we can
experience what Jesus was experiencing
on the cross, not to the
fulfillment of it. But just in that
>> that
family of experiences what he
experienced on the cross.
>> Yeah.
>> And we're Yeah. Because you're denying
yourself and he denied himself. He had
the power to take himself off the cross.
He did that for for love.
>> So like active righteousness, you can
actually do that. Hey, I'm going to fast
and I'm going to practice joy in the
midst of the sorrow of hunger.
>> Sorrow, right?
>> Yeah. That's a way you could practice
>> mercy.
>> Joy.
>> Yeah.
>> Can I say something on that?
>> Yes, please.
>> That one is definitely a hard one. um
having joy in the midst of fasting
>> and um just having to fast and then
probably everyone else around you is
eating and you go somewhere and um
>> go somewhere and someone is just talking
about something that involves food
>> and
you're it's hard
>> I don't know what to say. you get pissed
off and absolutely angry at the person
and all of a sudden this anger comes
down and you're like, "Oh my word,
what's wrong with you? Don't you know
fasting?"
And um it just really tells us that if
we don't practice the spirit of joy in
fasting, we are not going to enjoy the
fast
>> honestly. Because
>> if we can't enjoy and know, oh God, I'm
here fasting because of this issue in my
life or whatever is going on
>> and I know that you are there to comfort
me and through this time that I'm
fasting,
>> you are comforting me or filling my cup.
If we don't have the joy, we can't even
say anything of joy or thankfulness to
God because we're like, God, you know,
I'm just here because I'm struggling
>> and we're just fasting.
>> But if we have the joy when fasting,
when we're done fasting, we can sit
down, laugh about it, and just say,
"God, thank you so much for giving me
the joy of fasting, even when everyone
else around me is eating." So
>> yeah.
>> Um, so you could be fasting and sinning
at the same time.
>> Like I'm fasting but I'm mad
>> but I'm mad that that I'm envious that
my friend next to me can eat or that
Yeah. No, that's not the
>> Yeah, you're Thank you for sharing that
because you're right.
Absolutely. Absolutely.
>> Yeah, that's a that's a not just a
powerful thought but a powerful
challenge.
>> Yes, it is. you know, how can I
um and I think, you know, I mean, if we
look at fasting and the fruit of the
spirit, which again is kind of like
remember when Jesus said, "Man shall not
live by bread alone, but by every word
that proceeds out of the mouth of God."
>> He said that while he was fasting,
>> fasting. Wow. Amen. And so Jesus was
actually
>> he wasn't
some like wait what
>> while he was fasting he was also eating
>> the word of God.
>> He was eating the word of God.
>> He was eating the fruit of the spirit.
>> Yes.
>> Right. So I think a lot of times we
forget that
we think fasting is just abstaining from
food. M
>> but we can fast
>> and still eat
>> and also abstain from the word of God.
Also abstain from the fruit of the
spirit.
>> Right. Okay. I see what you're saying.
>> Right. We're we're supposed to be eating
the fruit of the spirit.
>> Eating.
>> As you eat of the fruit,
>> you get stronger in that fruit.
>> And that is the reason for I mean for a
fast is to because is to ha is to
strengthen your spiritual connection
with God. Yeah.
>> Because you're you are dependent upon.
we're always dependent upon him um
anyways, but you see it more clearly
when you're fasting. you are just more
in tune with okay God you know help me
to be able to accomplish all my
different things today because I'm
fasting and when food approaches me of
course your mind wants to automatically
I want to eat that you know but you know
he helps you to
>> take your mind somewhere else
>> and you say you're just more sensitive
to God's presence in your in your walk
on when you fast on that day it's like
you you there's no power within
yourself.
>> Yeah.
>> It's God.
>> Yep. Um
>> and your relationship with him gets more
personal and just more like almost like
you're hearing God's voice more clearly.
>> I can I experience that
>> like you're just more
>> in tune. I you know Yeah. You're just
more in tune with his voice.
>> So you know
>> it's not that God wants us to fast every
day.
>> We have to eat. But I'm just saying that
experience, that time that you set out
for fasting is a time that just kind of
fine-tunes, I think, your relationship
with God.
>> Yeah. Um, so when we talk about a water
fast,
>> or
uh, you know, a fruit fast,
>> we're saying, "Hey, we're not going to
we're not going to take anything into
our bodies except water."
A fruit fast
is saying, "Okay, I'm not going to eat
anything but the fruit of the spirit,"
>> right?
>> And you know, think of how
how powerful that would be.
>> To not just say, "I'm I'm I'm abstaining
from physical food, but
>> I'm going on a fruit fast."
>> Amen. So, I'm just going to be eating
fruit for the next, you know, however
many days or
>> and they even have intermittent fasting.
>> Amen.
>> You know,
>> and I and I like Yes. intermittent
fasting, too.
>> I'm going to I'm going to eat this
fruit. I'm going to eat of the fruit of
joy of the fruit of joy for the next uh
16 hour 16 hours. I'm going to eat the
fruit of joy. I'm going to eat the fruit
of peace. I'm going to eat the fruit of
longsuffering.
>> Amen. Right.
>> Amen.
>> A lot of ways for us to end to to learn
how to exercise and how to get stronger
in these different fruits.
>> Amen. Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Amen. No, I wanted to see if if Melinda
or Kazia had um a closing word because
we're getting ready to to close out um
Sabbath school, but and then we're we're
just I feel like are we halfway through?
>> So, what I'm going to say is we read one
sentence in this chapter.
>> Well, we can pick it up next. This is
why I love there's no
>> we just read one
>> just like you say sentence the word not
that your book is not ex but because the
word of God is is always given
>> this happened to us la sorry I didn't
want to interact
go ahead
>> last night in Friday night lights um we
were um Michaela and I and Miss Jerry we
were
>> um looking at Psalm 33 no 23
and we got two words two words into the
first verse. Two words, the Lord. And we
were talking for 90 minutes.
>> Wow.
>> That is beautiful, ladies. That is
absolutely
>> It was insane. It was insane.
>> Your Friday night
>> sounds amazing.
>> Go ahead, Casia.
>> It is.
I also have to say that about our also
we have another study we do on Thursdays
and we don't get that far into anything
before we start talking about the first
sentence or the first few words
>> and just it's so like the word of God is
so it's so sweet until sometimes we
cannot continue in reading more because
we have to just
>> soak in that first part before we move
on.
>> Yeah.
>> I now understand why we need eternity to
study the Bible because Miss Jerry was
saying last night, you know, we could
talk for the rest of our lives about
these two words, the Lord. And I was
like, yeah, we could. That's why we need
eternity to
>> Yep.
>> you know, get through the rest of Psalm
23.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen. You guys are such a
blessing. you're just you're the joy is
coming off of both of you and I know
that it's it's it's permeating here here
in the studio. So I know it's permeating
to all around the world to everyone that
is viewing. So no, we just thank you
guys for your commitment to God and um
just
>> who you are. It's it's truly a blessing.
Truly a blessing. Um,
well, we didn't get that far, but we
will continue next week and hopefully
both of you will be back with us. We
know
>> and I will read more sentences next
week.
>> Yeah, maybe. Maybe maybe just a few
words.
>> We'll see. Okay. Well, um, we want to
say a closing prayer. Maybe I would like
to have one of you guys pray. Please
close us out in prayer.
>> Which one shall it be, Kazilla?
Oh,
>> go ahead.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay, let's pray.
Dearly father, Lord, thank you so much
for bringing us here um today. Lord,
thank you so much for letting us get the
little bit that we needed to get today
from today's lesson. Um Lord, we pray
that you may fill us with your spirit of
joy because I know we struggle so much
with the spirit of joy and um we pray
Lord that you will fill us with it
because if we don't have it, Lord, we
can have no joy towards the the the the
love that you give towards us, Lord.
Lord, we pray that in everything we say
and everything that we do that we will
represent you.
And Lord, help us to remember that um
just
that you are here for us. You are here
to hear our prayers, to hear our
thoughts. And Lord, just knowing that
you are here with us here as we speak um
before you. We are not just here because
we're here, but we're your vessels and
we're speaking through you. Lord, we
pray that as we go through the main
service that you will fill us with um
with your spirit and bless pastor as he
gives us the message and that we may be
filled with your spirit. Lord, we pray
that in everything that we say and we do
and as we uh depart, we pray that you
will bless us and take care of us in our
separate ways. Bless um those who are in
the afternoon, those who are in the
morning, and for us who are going to
bed, we pray that you will protect us
from all harm and danger and keep us
safe. Lord, thank you so much for
bringing us all here tonight. In Jesus
name we pray and believe. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Thank you.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. And thank you everyone for for
viewing uh Sabbath school today. We are
about to go into the divine worship
service. Do you have anything you wanted
to share about your message?
>> Um the message today is on the man of
sin. Um and you know what I'm going to
say, so I'm not going to say it.
It's not what you think.
>> It's not what we think.
>> It's never what we think. So don't so
don't even try to think of what you
think it might be.
>> Okay? Please, this is the time right
now. You guys can uh be virtual Bible
workers for God. You can invite others
to church by sharing on your social
media. You can send the link to a friend
or family member, a co-orker, and say,
"Hey, I'd love for you to come to to
church with me today." So this is your
time right now. and whatever um platform
well you're watching on YouTube. So like
and subscribe because that helps us to
be able to go further into the virtual
world.
>> So please do that.
>> All right. So we'll see you in church.
Don't go away. Don't go anywhere.
[Music]
The South Pacific is a place of natural
wonder, a land where time slows down
amid the calm and peaceful scenes of
living creation. A place where the
gentle strumming of island music creates
a mellow mood fit for rest and
relaxation. But nothing is more soothing
than the sounds of nature.
From the crashing waves on white sandy
beaches to the rustling coconut trees
swaying in the cool island breeze, the
falling rain, the singing birds, the
babbling brook, the clapping waterfalls,
and the rushing rivers. But of all the
sounds of nature, nothing is quite like
the whales.
[Music]
The serenating of these gentle giants
was first recorded by accident at a top
secret hydrophone station off the coast
of Bermuda. Naval engineers were
listening for Russian submarines, but
instead they captured calling sounds
from the deep. Upon examining the
recordings, the startling discovery was
made that there was system and structure
in the songs. There was rhyming and
repetition, order and arrangement. Songs
would range from 6 to 30 minutes in
duration, slightly evolving yearbyear,
ever expanding in complexity and
creativity.
[Music]
Like the sweet serenating of a man to
his lover, male humpbacks in the same
general vicinity would sing the same
song during breeding season. The winner
of this aquatic song competition was
chosen by female humpbacks looking for
the singer to father their offspring.
[Music]
The syntax of the song structure
suggested an intelligence far beyond the
linear language of chirping birds,
mooing cows, barking dogs, or roaring
lions. Considered as one of the most
complex forms of communication in the
animal kingdom, the whale song is a
magical mystery.
But unfortunately, whales were hunted by
the tens of thousands each year,
slaughtered to the point of near
extinction.
But when the world heard these gentle
giants speak from the deep for the first
time, the rising awareness of their
intelligence and beauty ignited a
worldwide movement to save the whales. A
movement leading to the laws we have
today to protect and preserve these
magnificent creatures. Upon hearing
their voice, we wanted to do all we
could to cause their sufferings to
cease. We heard their cries and thus
wanted to save their lives.
Here in the tiny islands of Tonga, we've
had the incredible privilege of swimming
with the humpbacks and hearing their
love language firsthand. At up to 50 ft
in length and 79,000 lbs in weight, you
feel very small, weak, and vulnerable
swimming next to these massive mammals.
But our encounters with them the past
few days has given us a glimpse into the
character of the creator who fashioned
them with intelligence and design.
Powerful and yet peaceful, strong and
yet subtle, giant and yet gentle,
massive and yet majestic. Our God is the
same.
Our powerful creator is also kind and
compassionate. The majesty of the
heavens is also the meek and lowly one.
The sovereign of the universe is also
the sweet singer of Israel who rejoices
over us in love. It is he whom Zephaniah
wrote of when he spoke, "The Lord your
God in the midst of thee is mighty. He
will save. He will rejoice over thee
with joy. He will rest in his love and
he will joy over thee with singing.
And just like the whale song, the Lord
sings over us in everlasting love. We
are the joy and the rejoicing of his
infinite heart. And he desires us to
hear his voice that we might know his
heart, to hear his song that we might
experience his salvation. And those who
choose to dive deep in the ocean of his
word will hear the Savior's song of
salvation to us. And in that sweet
salvation song, we will discover
complexity, structure, intelligence,
beauty, creativity, and design. Design
that is calculated to capture our
imagination and to convict our hearts.
[Music]
And so today, I invite you to pause, go
deeper, be still,
listen, and listen carefully. And as you
do, the ear of faith will hear the sweet
harmonies of the heavenly song of
salvation. A song that will literally
take your breath away.
[Applause]
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
happy that you decided to continue to
worship with us today. Please let us
know where you are viewing from and if
this is your very first time, please put
a one in the chat. I want to say a
special welcome to you. But we are so
thankful to have all of you here with us
continuing to worship with us today. The
Sabbath school on joy and we just barely
scratched the surface uh today. But that
was just such a blessing to be able uh
to just talk about the fruit of the
spirit and how that really can help us.
how the fruit of the spirit joy and
we're going to be going deeper into it
next week, but how that can really help
us in this uh Christian war that we are
in that we are in in this battle as we
um are fighting uh the true enemy which
is that enemy within that tries to uh
cause us not to be able to have victory
in this Christian um art of war. And so,
um, it was just such a blessing to begin
to talk about joy and what that really
looks like. Looks like we have a one a
roads. Welcome to Living Mana Church.
While the others are still putting in
the chat where they're viewing from, I
just want to let you know um, our
firsttime viewer that we are a 100%
online church and we have programming
um, on mental health, on uh, your
physical health. On Mondays, we have
mental health, physical health is on
Tuesdays. Um, we have two prayer
services on Wednesdays. We have young
adult uh programming by our young adult
pastor on Thursdays and we obviously are
here on Sabbath as well. We have many
small groups and I'm going to tell you
in just a minute how you can join some
of those small groups if you are
interested. But we are just thankful
that you are here worshiping with us
today. And I'd like to say welcome um
from our viewer from Buford, Georgia.
Welcome to Living Mana Church. Happy to
see you here with us today. Um we have
Dawn from Oklahoma City. Welcome. We
have Mark from Joplain, uh Missouri.
Good to have you here with us. We have
uh Adelaide from New Jersey. Welcome,
Jerry. I saw you from San Diego. Always
good to see you here. Uh we have um from
Sauten, Virginia. Welcome to Living Mata
Church. Good to see you here. Ashley
from Dylan, North South Carolina. It's
good to see all of you and where you are
watching from from all around the
country and the world. Again, welcome to
Living Mana Church. We have a special um
announcement that we would like to um
have this this I can't say this morning
but today on Sabbath because it's a
different time zone for everybody but we
um would like to invite some of our um
members and our leaders in um a ministry
called give mana and that's sister uh
Shaunene and also sister Angela who is
the leader of our benevolence um our
benevolence uh committee here for Living
Mana Church. They are here with us today
for to share um a special announcement.
And guys, you know what? Um I don't have
my earpiece in. So, I am sorry that I'm
going to have to get my earpiece in, but
you guys can start sharing. Please share
with our viewing audience uh what you
are here to share with them. Sister
Shaun, you can go first.
Hello everyone.
My name is Shaunine Baker, Sister Baker,
and I am one of the team leads for Give
Mana Ministries.
Uh Give Man Mana Ministries is a social
and practical
uh practical resource national network
ministry.
We are here to support and encourage
the culture a culture of Christ to serve
in a variety of ways. Uh we serve with u
practical needs. We serve by setting up
resources. We we search them out and we
share them. And how you find those is on
money networks. you go to give mana and
then you will go under
um community and then you can read all
about us. You can read our about page,
what we do and our mission statement. We
also do practical um
free online classes for uh healthy
cooking. We have a business directory in
the works that is coming up. So go there
and check us out on money networks. We
are always looking for ambassadors for
your state. So you sign up under your
state. When you go under give matter,
you'll see all your states there. Please
sign up. And with the climate today,
there is such a need for many resources
in whether it's for health,
economically, spiritually. So we are
here to pray with you for you. We have
an amazing of course prayer team as
well. So we are looking forward to
having ambassadors in each state. So
please email us at give mana ministries.
Give mana I'm sorry give mana at living
mana.sh.
Okay. So it should be under you should
see it under the um in the uh
tab where the chats are.
>> Yes.
>> It is very important that we share
our any type of resource that we know.
So we just ask each of you to um send
them in to us at that email address and
we will post them. And we just pray that
um every God continues uh to keep each
and every one of us. I pray that each of
us stays blessed and um we again are
here to support you.
>> And sister Angela has some more
information for you. I don't know. Can
you guys hear me?
>> So we are um
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Good. Good. Okay. Wonderful. No,
thank you sister and Shaunie. Thank you
for for sharing that. Um, Sister Shaine,
you can't hear me.
>> Okay. But sister, sister Angela, you can
hear me?
>> I can. I hope you can hear me.
>> Yes, I can hear you as well. So, yes,
please. I know you have something to
share to follow up what sister Shaunine
was sharing.
>> Yes. So, um, happy Sabbath everyone
first and foremost. Um so I am heading
up the uh benevolence uh department and
so we know as sister Shaine mentioned
we are living in different times and
people are going to at some point or
another may need some assistance or
help. Um and so we want to as a church
uh we want to be um able to um
to be a blessing um to our members,
right? Um one of the things I was
looking at um last night was um a little
story in um I think Acts the 9th
chapter. It talks about a woman named
Darcus, uh, also known as Tabitha, and
how she, uh, was giving, um, out of her
heart by sewing clothes and making
clothes for people, uh, in need. And
when she got sick and fell to her death,
uh Peter got word. He came to uh where
she was. I think it was uh Japa. And uh
he raised her from the dead, right? And
so one of the things that really strikes
out at me regarding that whole thing is
just our love to want to help others.
And that's where benevolence comes in
at.
uh wanting to give to others because
>> um in the United States we're seeing all
kinds of different things happening. I
know um in the state of Missouri, we
recently received notification that no
one in the state of Missouri would be
receiving any food stamps for the month
of um November, right? Um and so there
going to be a number of families who may
start seeing um ends not meeting or
really struggling and so we want our
church to be in position to help our
church members directly because
>> yeah is that directly because of the
government shutdown current the current
government
>> the government shutdown absolutely
absolutely for now that just includes
the food stamps which is also known as
the SNAP food program But
>> right
>> in December it could be disability or
social security benefits or you know
health insurance or Medicare or
Medicaid.
>> And so we want to be able to be a
blessing when those things those trickle
down effects of uh financial crisis uh
start.
>> Uh for me um my whole everything now
that I am considered disabled is really
wrapped up in the government. So, I
don't pretend not to be concerned with,
oh my gosh, what am I going to do?
Right. Right.
>> Um, but I will share with you that
>> I think that God wants us to be a
cheerful giver according to the word of
God and he will bless what we what it is
that we sow. So for me, I have made a
decision to cancel my Netflix
>> and I will divert those funds and begin
to give every month on a reoccurring
basis to the benevolence fund
>> so that when families are in crisis and
they need those dollars that living
manner would be able to to be able to
help.
>> Amen. Amen.
Amen. Yes. We're so happy to be able to
have a benevolence fund that is, you
know, able to to help where we can. Um
when we are able to help those who um
are in need. And you're right, Sister
Angela and Sister Shaunie. This is u we
are in some trying times um here um in
this country. And so um we um are
thankful and I will be sharing when we
do the tithe and offering here shortly
how people can give. Um so I'll be
sharing with you how you'll be able to
do that. But I do thank you both for
coming on and just allowing our viewing
audience to know uh what is there and
how it can be used and that the ministry
of give mana. So again you can find give
mana. Maybe we can put the link back in
the chat again because it was in there.
But you can go to Mighty Networks um and
on Mighty Networks you will be able um
to find out about the resources that can
may be available for you in your state
and connect in that way. And there you
can see the graphic. You can email uh
give mana or you can text mana to that
855 number and you will be able to get
all the information um that you are
needing. So again, thank you both for
being um here with us and sharing um
with our viewing audience. Um it is a
blessing again to have the give mana and
sister Angela the benevolence uh fund
and the committee that that helps to be
able to um be able to help people who um
are in need. So again, we say thank you
um for for the ministry and for all that
you both do for Living Mana Church. Uh
well, with that said, I just want to
give you some more announcements. Uh
here from Living Mana Church, we just
talked about I gave that I gave that 855
number and some of you could be say,
"What is that?" Especially if you're a
first time a first timer. Well, that
here's what this is. This is how you can
stay connected to Living Manage Church.
You can sign up to get text alerts. Um,
and you do that by texting LMOC
to8552074107
and you that signs you up automatically
to get text alerts. So that's here. If
you're in North America, please sign up
to get these text alerts. uh for our
first timers and you're just learning
about uh our church and the ministry
that we do here, you're going to want to
do this if you're here in North America
because it will remind you of when we're
going live with Mental Health Monday,
which we have a new uh mental health
Monday this week. Dr. Ricardo White and
myself will be doing a live new program.
Um or when we're doing True Health
Tuesdays with Maria Hmel. Um, and she is
a doctor, Maria I should say, and is a
licensed um, nutritionist who is sharing
all of her information that God has
blessed her with uh, on how we can have
healthy bodies. But you'll be reminded
of these events that are happening and
of our prayer services and all of the
things that we're doing here at Living
Mana Church. That's you want to sign up
to get text. That's if you're here in
North America. If you are not in North
America, which we have many uh viewing
audience and members who are not, you're
going to want to get on Mighty Networks
and we were just talking about that. Um,
but Mighty Network is our virtual church
home. This is where you're going to get
announcements here on Mighty Networks.
You'll get notifications, reminders.
You'll get to see our small groups. Um,
you'll get to meet different members
here on Mighty Networks. You get to see
the leaders of different small groups.
There's this is our virtual home. This
is where we form community and this is
where our family meets virtually. Um,
outside of being here for church, this
is where you can personally get to know
each other a little bit better. So,
Mighty Networks is where it's at. So,
the the link for Mighty Networks is in
the chat. And so, you're going to want
to sign up for Mighty Mighty Networks so
that you can stay connected to Living
Man. And most importantly, we can stay
connected to you because we want you to
be a part of our church family and we
want to all be connected together. Uh
just to let you guys know that we do
have
uh children's programming and that is
Elamosi Kids and they meet on uh
Saturday at 11:30 p.m. Central time.
They run for about an hour and a half.
If you want to get your child involved
with LMOC Kids, please email uh the that
email there on your screen,
lamoscidmmanana.urch
or you can text kids to that 855 number.
And I can tell you uh that our kids
ministry is a blessing uh just like our
youth ministry is. Uh it's just a a
blessing what our young people are
learning here at Living Mana Church. And
so our leadership is doing a great job.
Also, Pastor Meyers does have virtual
office hours. So if you are interested
in meeting with this pa with the pastor,
all you have to do is schedule an
appointment. The email is there. Patrice
living.live. That is how you're able to
schedule an appointment with pastor
meers. So if you again need to speak
with him, that is how you do that. If
you'd also are interested in
transferring your membership or becoming
a member, I should say, there are three
different ways that you can do that. And
that email that you see on your screen
can be used for all of those ways. Um,
and you can either trans if you are a
7th day Adventist member already and you
want to join Living Manage Church, you
can have your membership transferred. If
you are a Christian and you are studying
and learning about the things that se
the seventh day adventist church teaches
from the Bible, you can have you can
join by profession of faith or if you
would like to be baptized uh pastor
Myers will baptize you. And so and that
is another way that you can join Living
Mana Church. We have a baptism coming up
on the 15th of November and we are
excited about that. Just want to remind
you guys that we do have the pray the
prayer power line which is on Wednesdays
after our power Wednesday programming.
We have the power line and this is
really I say it all the time but this is
a way to evangelize and to to others and
invite them to a program that Living
Matter Church is doing but it's through
prayer and it's sincerely we want to
pray for them as well. So, this is on
Wednesday evenings at 8:00 PM Central
time. You put your prayer in the chat
and we have there's live prayer over
your prayer request right then. All we
do on the power line is pray. So, if you
know someone um a friend, a family
member, a co-orker, they saying they
need prayer, invite them to the power
line and they will get to see their
prayer being prayed over. or if they
want to give you your prayer, their
prayer request, you can bring it to the
power line for them. But the power line
again is Wednesdays at 8:00 PM on
YouTube. You can see there um Central
Standard Time.
Also want to remind you guys of
Hangouts. Hangouts is just an amazing
ministry uh that has been started here
at Living Man Church and it's been such
a blessing. I've been able to attend two
of them. Planning to attend tomorrow's
at 6:30 p.m. Pastor Myers and I will
both be there just hanging out with you
guys. It is so much fun to get to know
um our our viewing audience and our
church members just that much better and
to get closer um with with all of you.
So, it's a lot of fun. So, please join
us for a very special hangouts on
Sunday, October 19th at 6:30 p.m.
Central Standard Time. Uh, this Sunday,
the men are taking over the hangout.
That should be fun, guys. Um, all your
virtual hosts for the evening will be
gentlemen from LOC. They will guide you
through ice breakers, meaningful
dialogue, share hobbies, interest, and
help us get to know each other better.
Uh we um let's see we all start out
together in the main Zoom meeting and
then they break up into uh smaller
groups. I think no more than 10. So
don't worry if you have um any anxiety
about big big uh forms or spots or those
type of things. You don't have to worry.
This is very uh just low-key fun and you
get to know get to know each other
better. So, I'm excited about Hangouts
tomorrow and hopefully we'll get to see
you there. Looking forward to seeing you
there.
All right. I want to tell you guys about
Kingdom Principles.
Kingdom Principles is um another
ministry that's happening here at Living
Man Church. Get ready. Something
powerful is on the horizon. Pastor Loami
Richardson is unveiling Kingdom
Principles, a dynamic new series
designed to anchor your life and and
clarify conviction and and kingdom
truth. This isn't feel-good fluff. It's
spiritual infrastructure, a framework
for believers who are done drifting and
already all ready to build. They are
ready to build with purpose. If you've
been hungry for depth, strategy, and a
divine reset, this is your moment. From
identity to impact, these principles
will reshape how you live, lead, and
walk in the spirit. Coming coming soon,
and it's about to change everything. So,
that's kingdom principles with our young
adult pastor, Lammy Richardson. So,
you're not going to want to miss that.
and you will have if you sign up to get
those text alerts in our almighty
networks, you're going to be alerted to
when he is going live. So, you're going
to want but his programmings are on
Thursday evening. So, you're going to
want all that information.
I want to tell you guys about Friday
night Sabbath school here at uh Living
Matter Church. As you know, we do have
Sabbath school on Sabbath morning, but
those are not the traditional Sabbath
schools with the quarterly. So on Friday
night, we do have a more traditional
Sabbath school. This isn't uh your
typical Sabbath school. Gyms invites you
to walk through the quarterly with fresh
eyes, open hearts, and bold questions.
We're not just reading. We're wrestling,
reflecting, and reimagining what it
means to live the word. Because of the
word
deserves more than routine, it deserves
revelation. Whether you're new to the
quarterly or a lifelong student, this
space is for you. Expect deep dives,
honest dialogue, and spirit-led
discovery. Come ready to think, share,
and grow. Details
uh are on will be on they are on mighty
networks and all you have to do is text
gems to that 855 number that you see on
your screen.
Okay. The women's ministry. We're
excited about the women's ministry um as
well here at Living Man Church. Uh you
are seen, you are called, you belong.
The women's ministry is more than a
gathering. It's a movement of grace,
growth, and godly strength. Whether you
are leading, learning, um healing, or
just showing up with questions, there's
a place for you here. We meet, pray,
study, serve, and support one another
one another and every season of life.
It's a space to be real, be refreshed,
and be reminded of your purpose. Come
connect with women who are walking in
faith, rising in courage, and building
something eternal together. Join us um
on um join us, your story matters here,
and you can text women to that 855
number. So now you guys are seeing how
important it is to have that uh 855
number and to to join them there. It's
so very important to be able to um get
those reminders and that information.
Want to also remind you guys how you can
continue to give to support Living uh
Mana Church and you can do that
virtually uh by going to Adventist
giving
and I adventgiving.org.
There you will see a virtual tithe
envelope and I have to say before I say
this, you guys have been such a blessing
and so faithful in your giving. So thank
you. But the way that you can continue
to give is to go to adventistgiving.org
org and then you can if you don't have
an account create an account but then
you can log in and um if it's saved it's
automatically going to go to uh living
mana of the northeastern conference as
you can see there on your screen a
virtual tithe envelope is there and you
will be able to give your tithe which
goes to support the uh northeastern
conference of the 7th day Adventist
church you'll see there there's the
local church which that is the when you
give to the there that helps us to do
all the things that we do here uh for
living mana and also uh there's the
benevolence uh fund and you will see
other things there on your uh tithe
envelope and so if that's how you can
give virtually to continue to support
the mission the ministry and this church
of living mana and the worldwide church
uh the 7th day Adventist church if you
are wanting not wanting um to give
virtually but are wanting to mail in
your tithe and your offering. You were
able to do that as well. You could do
that by going to PO or sending it to P.
Box 428 Owens Crossroads, Alabama 35763.
And please put a note that how much is
for tithe, how much is for offering, or
if there's or if you're wanting to
support another ministry on that tithe
envelope, um you're able to do that as
well. but just let us know where you
would like um your funds to go. So
again, just want to say thank you for
supporting Living Mana Church. Um in
this coming April, we will have been
here for four years. So we have been
here for three and a half years. And
that is because of your faithfulness to
God and helping to support Living Mana
Church. Not just through monetarily, but
also through your presence and through
sharing uh about this church and talking
to people um about this church. This is
how we've been able to grow and just to
be able to go into all the world. And so
again, thank you for your faithfulness.
I just want to say a prayer of
thanksgiving to God at this time. So, if
you'd please just bow your heads with me
as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, we just thank you
for your Sabbath, Lord. We thank you for
the rest that it brings, Lord. And we're
studying the fruit of the spirit joy,
Lord, and the joy we get out of keeping
the Sabbath, Lord, when we get to just
spend 24 hours just to spend with you.
We don't have to worry about work. We
don't have to worry about school. We
don't have to worry about any other
thing but just to worship you. And
that's the gift that you gave us in the
Sabbath, Lord. And we thank you for
that. Lord, I thank you for the
faithfulness of so many who help to keep
Living Mana Church going and they are
just such a blessing and it's because of
you. They're responding to you um
touching their heart and so Lord, we
praise you for that as well. Lord, I
know so many that are viewing now, they
have different burdens on their hearts.
Lord, they have burdens um about a
marriage or about a child or a health
issue, a financial issue. Lord, there's
so many things that we your children go
through on this earth. But Lord, I lift
up every burden that this viewing
audience and for those who are going to
watch later, Lord, is experiencing right
now. You know what those burdens are,
Lord. So, I ask that you will show up in
their situation. Show them that you are
here for them and that you love them and
that you care and you hear their
prayers, Lord. You are such a faithful
God because you do that for each and
every one of us so faithfully. And Lord,
I want to lift up Pastor Meyers um the
message that you have given to him that
the Holy Spirit would help him to
deliver that message and that it would
touch all of our hearts and we will
leave this church service changed for
the better. Lord, we ask all of these
things in your precious in the precious
name of Jesus. Amen.
Think God can't use you?
Think he only uses perfectly qualified
people?
Take a closer look.
[Music]
Moses was not a great speaker.
Jonah ran from God.
Jacob was a liar.
Noah got drunk.
Rahab was a prostitute.
David had an affair.
Jeremiah was depressed a lot.
Solomon was rich in wisdom but poor in
lifestyle. John the Baptist was just
plain poor.
Timothy was too young. Abraham was too
old. Lazarus was dead.
Sarah was barren. Naomi was a widow.
Gideon and both doubted. And so did
Sarah. Peter lacked self-control.
James and John were self-righteous.
Paul had a short fuse. Well, so did
Peter and Moses. Actually, lots of
people did.
God's army isn't perfect. It never has
been. It's the march of the unqualified.
Get in line.
[Music]
I keep fighting voices in my mind that
say I'm not enough.
Every single lie that tells me I will
never measure up.
>> Am I more than just the sum of every
high and every low?
Remind me once again just who I am
because I need to know.
>> You say I am loved
when I can't feel a thing.
You say I am strong
when I think I am weak.
And you say I am
when I am falling short.
And when I
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens.
Oh, I believe
what you say of me.
I believe
>> the only thing that matters now is
everything you think of me.
Oh,
>> in you I find my worth. In you I find my
identity.
[Music]
Oh,
you say I am lost when I can't feel a
thing.
You say I am strong
and I think I am weak.
You say I am held
when I am falling short.
But when I don't belong.
You say I'm yours
and I believe. Oh. Oh. I believe
what you say of me.
I believe.
[Music]
>> Love came down and rescued me. Love came
down and set me free. I am yours.
I am forever yours.
Mountains higher, valley low, I sing
out, remind my soul that I am yours.
I am forever yours. You say I am loved.
When I can't feel a thing.
And you say I am strong.
When I think I am weak.
You say I am held
when I am fall short.
And when I don't belong.
Well, you say I am yours.
And I am yours.
I am yours.
All my days,
Jesus. I am yours.
I am yours.
I am yours
from all my days.
Jesus, I am yours
and I believe.
Oh, I believe
what you say of me.
I believe.
[Music]
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
[Music]
Greetings saints.
>> Amen.
Happy Sabbath everyone.
Happy Sabbath. Praise God.
>> Praise God. Praise God. Praise God. You
can see and hear us. Not sure if we're
connected. If we are,
>> we are.
>> We are. Amen. Amen. Always a blessing to
be here. Thank you. Thank you. Blessings
to you. What a wonderful Sabbath day.
Always a blessing to be here with my
lovely wife Jackie. We'll be sitting in
for our beloved prayer team leaders Amra
and brother Terry which are out
traveling today. Give them our blessings
and
>> may God be with them today.
>> Amen.
>> And uh just thankful to be here.
>> Amen. Amen. You know, I'm just it's just
such an honor. It's such a blessing to
have such wonderful prayer leaders.
>> I call them servant leaders. Um brother
Terry and Sister Amra. They're just a
blessed beautiful couple. And I tell
you, um, I I tell you, they they're so
inspirational. I know they're
inspirational in our lives. The entire
prayer team, you know, God um they both
have a great gift that they're using
mightily for the Lord. And it's it's
such a blessing nowadays to see people
go forth and allow God to use them.
They're a blessing to you and my life,
huh?
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> We do miss them when they're away.
>> Yes, we do.
>> Praise God. Yeah. Praise God. and and
you know, we just uh um
thank everyone for being with us today
and um I guess we'll get started with
our praise reports. How about that?
>> Yes. Yeah. We don't have a lot of
prayers today, but just know
>> our praise reports.
>> Praise reports.
>> Yeah. Yeah. We're gonna do praise We'll
do the praise reports uh first. And I
just want to before I start, I want to
encourage you when God blesses you, when
God answer prayer, do not neglect to
give him praise. send those praise
reports in because you become a conduit
through which God can use to encourage
someone else to increase someone else's
faith who may be going through the same
situation or a like situation. So don't
forget to send that praise report in.
And yes, you know, so often we want an
opportunity to brag about our God,
right? That's your time. That's your
That's your open window to brag about
our God, to lift him up so the world
would know that he is yet on his throne.
He is a miracle working God sustaining
his people for great is his
faithfulness. I do want to encourage you
to do that and I'm going to get started
with our praise report. And I'm going to
start I think our first prayer praise
report, you know, is for Locc family.
You know, we're headed praising God. We
are headed towards four years of
ministry and we're praising and thanking
God. God has brought us a mighty long
way. You know, I hear the stories. We
didn't start with the ministry, but you
know, it was God has blessed. God has
provided. God has sustained. And I'm
sure God has done exceedingly abundantly
more than we have even thought of asked.
So, all praises go to our God for LOC
headed toward our four years of
ministry. God is is yet he's moving.
He's enlarging our territory and doing
great things through this living mana
team. So through this leadership team,
the members, praise God. That's and and
and that's a beautiful praise report.
>> Amen.
>> Sister Maja, she says, "Praise God for
moving in my situation and providing for
me for his blessings and mercy and for
his love." Amen. Praise God. We lift him
up. We glorify our God. The Bible says
that God says, "I delight in mercy."
>> Praise God. Amen.
>> I have another praise report um
from um from Ardub says uh your prayers
are life saving. Our prayers are life
saving regardless of what we see. Praise
God.
I thank y'all for the prayers and belief
we hold in Christ Jesus. Amen. you know,
he they're still continue to have
challenges uh um and and ask us continue
to pray for them as they seek resolution
to their situation. The Lord has blessed
them with resources and uh they they
haven't recovered all the funds yet, but
God has blessed them. Praise God. and
asking us to continue uh to keep them in
prayer, continue to pray for their
provision. Um
and and and go on and express that they
are strong in the Holy Spirit even
though the flesh may be weak. Uh they
continue to pursue God's purposes for
their lives seeking the Holy Spirit
daily. And one also want to share that
they are praying for all who are
struggling and in deceit to be resolved
in God's mercies. Hallelujah. We are
praying in the mighty and powerful
resolving name of Jesus. Amen. You know
sometimes I learn through this journey
of being a prayer warrior
>> that
a lot of times we don't see what God is
doing even through our prayers.
Sometimes this this prayer is what we
need is is is to sustain you during the
journey. Right. Yes.
>> May you may not see everything that you
want to see all at once, but through
these prayers they're sustaining you.
God is working to sustain you, to lift
you up, to strengthen you, to help you
endure, to keep your psyche sometimes,
right?
>> Amen.
>> Praise God. Praise God, brother Dub, for
this beautiful praise report. And we
will continue to pray for you and your
family. Pray with expectation because we
have a miracle working God. I have
another praise report. Uh Georgie Diggs,
she says, uh this report says, "Today
marks a monumental milestone. It's been
five years in the making. Today, I will
undergo under undergo surgery to remove
my port, a device that has been both my
lifeline and a constant reminder of my
five-year journey with cancer. This port
has played a crucial role in my
treatment, allowing me to receive
lifesaving chemotherapy that would have
been impossible to administer through a
traditional IV. The chemicals used in
chemotherapy are incredibly potent and
would have damaged her veins. But this
device enabled direct access to the
artery which were mere inches from the
heart. Over the course of her treatment,
the port has been accessed countless
times and even when not in use, it
required regular maintenance, including
flushes every six weeks. It has also
provided access for numerous CT and
brain scans, contrast imaging, and blood
tests. Using the port required a
specialized needle that resembled a
thumbtack which protruded from my chest,
making it visible through my clothing.
While some people couldn't help but
stare, I never minded as this device
represented my resilience and
determination. Praise God.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Praise God. The fact that I made it to
this point nearly two years after my
stem cell transplant is a testament to
my strength and the incredible support
system that has carried me through this
journey. I am thrilled that my medical
team believes I no longer need the port
as it symbolizes a major victory in my
battle against cancer. Hallelujah.
>> Hallelujah. While I wouldn't say I've
beaten cancer, I am grateful to be in
remission. And I recognize that this
achievement would not have been possible
without the love, care, and generosity
of my family, friends, doctors, and even
strangers who have supported me
spiritually, emotionally, and
financially. I am deeply thankful for
the lessons I've learned along the way,
including the importance of cherishing
every moment, mending relationships, and
expressing gratitude to those who matter
most.
Being diagnosed with cancer has been a
blessing in disguise as it has taught me
to appreciate the beauty of life and to
focus on the things that truly matter.
As I move forward, I am committed to
spreading kindness, compassion, and
gratitude, and to being a source of
inspiration, and hope for others. I
strive to be a man worthy of the gifts.
Hallelujah. I've received, and I am
excited to see what the future holds.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Praise God. that was inspirational to
me, you know, just sitting there reading
through your your journey
>> and you know, I know sometimes it's hard
for us and we've not experienced it. The
many the many x-rays, the many back and
forth. Sometimes our patients feel that
they live at the hospital with this type
of diagnosis. But even through that, we
saw God's provision for God's sustenance
and giving us strength to endure and not
giving up. Hallelujah. And this pray and
this praise report is is is just I mean
it speaks of that so bountifully. Thank
you for sharing and I pray that this uh
praise report let it be an inspiration
for others that may be going through
things. May it encourage you and inspire
you. I have another one other praise
report from our dub. I think I've yeah
I've already read that one. So oh none
of I have another one. I'm sorry. M
>> and uh this was a a praise report. Um
and uh we got a I remember this coming
to the prayer team. Um, I think it was
from It says we um um
it was a a a request that the older
brother had been sick for over a month
and went for a follow-up visit the other
day and uh and they believed that, you
know, they they gave us a diagnosis of
course that they needed a biopsy. Well,
the biopsy results did come back and the
biopsy results were not what they
expected. But this is the praise report.
It says um uh a pastor has gone to see
him and he has accepted God on a profess
profession of faith. Hallelujah. The
Bible tells me that the angels rejoice
when one's soul comes home to the
father. When one souls reconcile back to
the father because the angels rejoice,
we should too. Hallelujah. Praise God
for that. So brothers and sisters, be
encouraging the Lord and uh we're going
to go on to prayer now because we don't
want to hold up the time. We're anxious
to hear pastor's message. Amen.
>> And so um uh brother Danny, do you want
to go through your pray your uh prayer
request?
>> Only a few on the list.
>> I do have some as well.
>> Okay. So I will pray for for these. And
we we normally just cover the prayer
request, but we wants to pray for some
and I will pray for some. So thank you.
And I'm just still rejoicing in those
praise reports this.
>> Amen.
>> When baptism, when somebody gets
baptized, we're very passionate. I still
bold today when people get baptized and
and come to the Lord. I still
>> excited and to hear that testimony. Mr.
>> Georgina Digs.
>> Ge. Yes.
>> We're praising with you, sister. Praise
God. Thank you for sharing that powerful
testimony.
>> I do get excited when souls come to the
Lord. I tell you, I can just
>> that is just that it just brings me to
tears.
>> It does.
>> And I know it brings our father in
heaven to tears, you know, that this is
what he gave his son for, right? To
reconcile the world back to him and to
see souls, you know, to uh Yes. Praise
God.
>> Blessings to those I see in the chat
saying, "Happy Sabbath, Clarks." And
>> Amen. Yes. Happy Saturday. Bless you
back, sir.
>> Thank you
>> with our church family. We love our
church family. We love Eloc. We love our
pastor and his beloved wife. We love all
the leadership here. And I tell you, my
husband and I tell brother Terry all the
time, we're the ones that's blessed. We
feel so blessed.
>> Truly are.
>> Yes. And God has just grown us in so
many ways.
And that's what we look for. We wanted
to grow more. We wanted to be stretched.
And we're going to be stretched even
more. And we praise God for this for
this family, this worldwide ministry.
Glad I we're glad to be a part of this
prayer team ministry. It's a worldwide
ministry reaching people across the
world because you know what? Prayer
changes things. Prayer changes things.
Prayer changes people. Prayer changes
circumstances and they change
situations. Hallelujah. I have no doubt
when we go to pray, our God in heaven,
our father, he goes to work on behalf of
those petitions in which we're living to
the throne of grace and mercy.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. As we go to the throne of
grace, be encouraged, be uh just be on
be in agreement with us as we always do.
>> There's power in in in numbers. And as
we be in agreement, there's so much
power in that. We believe in that
though.
>> Yes. So pray with us.
>> Pray with us. and uh and be in agreement
with us.
>> Amen.
>> Cuz man, I'm telling you, it sets off an
explosion of faith and God moves. Moves.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> You know, sometimes I wonder if we had a
day where this worldwide church
was on their knees in prayer, boy, ain't
no telling what we would see.
>> What would we see?
>> That would be beautiful, wouldn't it?
But let's go to prayer, brother Clark.
>> Amen. Heavenly Father, let's go. Let us
pray, saints, as we go to the throne of
prayers. Father, thank you again today
for the power and the privilege of
prayer. Father, we honor it, Father. We
trust in it. We stand on your word,
Father, because your word is just
faithful. You are faithful, Lord, and
you've never lost a battle. You inspire
us to come to the throne of grace. So,
Father, we come humbly. And Father, we
ask that you cleanse our hearts, Lord,
and uh touch us, Lord, and bless us,
make us clean vessels as we make
intercession for your people today,
Lord. Bless them and cover them, Lord.
We say thanks in advance father because
this is your will father in the mighty
name of Jesus. Lord we lift up every
petition Lord. Everyone that's before
you right now Lord trusting in your holy
power and hand to move on their behalf
Lord in Jesus name. Father thank you.
>> Thank you Lord.
>> Thank you in advance Lord.
>> Thank you God for
>> by faith Lord. We lift up these prayers
and all the requests to you today right
now by faith. And I'm praying right now
for requests from from Margot. pray for
my daughter and her nephew
>> that they go to churchmen and have a
>> let me read my writing here for the
first time. Amen. They want to go to
church with they ask to go to church
with Hallelujah Father in the name of
Thank you for touching their hearts
Lord. Thank you for using her Lord and
and allowing them to to go with her
Lord. We just pray father that you go
forth Lord and make a way for them Lord
that they hear a word from you today.
Yes, Lord and continue this journey
Lord. Don't let it be a one-time event,
Lord. Continue to walk with them,
minister to them, and draw them close to
you, Father, in the precious name of
Jesus. Lord, thank you, Lord, for making
her a vessel. Yes, Lord, to to uh to be
there for them, Lord, and go there,
Lord. Be that light, Lord, in the mighty
name of Jesus. Lord, we ask your
blessings be upon them. Yes. In Jesus
name I pray. Amen. When brother James
has a request in for Regina Lambert,
Lord, that lost her brother Derek. Lord,
he passed away and I believe he was in a
ministry. Father, we ask you to bless
his family, Lord, in the name of Jesus.
You may your comfort be with them, Lord.
Give them peace, Lord, in the mighty
name of Jesus. Lord, help them to hold
on during this season, in this time in
their life. Lord, we know it's painful.
We know it hurts, but Father, let them
know that you are there, Lord, on their
behalf. Lord, continue to strengthen
them, Lord, in the mighty name of Jesus.
Lord,
>> uh I praise you and I thank you for this
prayer request. We just lift this family
up to you, Lord, and asking you to touch
them in a mighty powerful way. In Jesus
name I pray. Amen.
>> And father, I think brother pray uh
brother James has another prayer request
for uh for the Todd and his family. I
think that's a beautiful we pray for our
brother and his ministry Lord his family
Lord continue to bless him and use him
Lord what a powerful ministry he has
father spreading that love and the word
through all the videos and so what a
blessing Lord I too enjoy Lord so Lord
continue to use brother Todd Lord and
send his uh help him spread his word all
over the world father in Jesus name and
everything him and his family his
ministry stand in need of father your
hands will provide
>> in Jesus
anoint him, bless him, cover him off in
the name of Jesus I pray. Amen.
>> Amen. And Lita Peterson had request. She
said, "Please pray for our family, uh,
Don Tasha Atasha's family." That's a
prayer request for her that they may
come to know you. Hallelujah, Father.
Father, that is our desire and your
desire, Lord, for people to come to know
you, Lord. Open up areas of opportunity,
Lord, that they may be put people in
their lives and in their past, Lord, and
bless them. Open their ears and their
eyes that they may hear you, Lord.
Manifest yourself in their life in a
mighty powerful way, Lord. That they may
come to love, trust, and know you in the
name of Jesus I pray. God. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Uh, Sister Esita,
>> pray for a spiritual healing and
physical healing. Hallelujah. Father,
thank you for that request, Lord. We
lift her up to you by faith, Lord. Pray
that you will uh uh bless them, anoint
them, Lord, that they can be healed,
Father. Spiritual healing, Lord,
whatever it stands in need of, Father,
you know what's what they need, Lord.
Asking for growth, Lord. Spiritual
healing.
>> And bless them mightily, Lord. And touch
them in the way that only you can touch
them, Lord. Give them another love. let
them go from glory to glory and and
spiritual growth and and and and just uh
just faith and strength, Lord, in every
walk and aspect of their lives, Father
God. And just pray, Lord, for healing,
Lord, in Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. We lift up sister
Christiey's request for a 90 yearear-old
grandmother asking for prayer for her
daughter Melissa who she lost her
daughter, Lord God, in the name of
Jesus. Father, you know that pain. You
know that you know that hurt, Father.
And Father, we just lift her up to you
in the mighty name of Jesus. Father,
>> heal her. Give her strength, Lord. Walk
with her, Lord. And don't let the enemy
play on this sick circumstances and
emotions and sickness. Lord, keep her
strong.
>> And Father, in the name of Jesus, Lord,
uh, continue to walk with her, Lord.
Bless her family and all those that that
that uh that in her family, Lord, that
are hurting, too. we just put them in
your hands in the name of Jesus I pray.
Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. That's all I have.
>> Amen. Sister Veronica uh has uh uh she
has a request for unspoken prayers. We
you know Sister Veronica, God sees, God
hears, and he knows. Hallelujah. Brother
Rain, he says, "Please pray for me. I'm
struggling. I need the lies from Satan
to get out of my head. I can't explain
more." Hallelujah. You don't have to.
God knows all things. He hear your cry,
brother Rain. He see the sincerity and
honest ear h earnestness of your heart.
The word says when the uh when the enemy
comes in like a flood, the spirit of the
Lord lifts up a standard against him. So
send stand strong my brother stand
strong in the Lord trusting in his
neverchanging hand. Pansy pansy it says
uh please keep my family and I in
prayers especially my son Wanza and
friend Gray. Most heavenly and gracious
father, Lord, I lift up these petitions
and Lord so many more. I lift up Lord
the families, everyone that's Lord
that's that's in here at Living Loc
today with unspoken requests. I lift up
everyone who has heaviness and uh and
burdened hearts. I lift up those that
feel discouraged. I lift up those that
may be experiencing anxiety. I lift up
everyone, Lord, that's struggling, that
may be dealing with depression, whatever
the situation or the circumstance may
be. Father, we bring it to your throne
with expectation. Your word tells us to
call on you and you will answer and show
us great and mighty things that that we
know not of. Father, your children are
crying out. They're crying out for
healing, mental, emotional,
uh spiritual, Lord, uh as well as
physical healing. Father, we're praying
for financial healing. So many,
especially, Lord, hospitalizations
impose such a financial burden upon so
many families, even those that have that
that have insurance. Father, we're
praying for those that have lost access
to SNAPS programs and Lord, other things
that may have affected their uh their
monthly income. Father, we come to your
throne of mercy and grace. We're
standing, oh God, before you in crying,
have mercy, oh Lord, have mercy. Have
mercy on your people and hear their cry.
Hear their call, oh God. For we're
crying out to you, our father that is in
heaven, our only father who has never
lost a battle. Lord, we know that you
care. We know that you're merciful,
Lord, unto us. Father, move your mighty
hand. Father, we're praying for
marriages that may be on the brink of
divorce. We're praying for homes, oh
God, that's in chaos. We're praying for
lives that's in chaos. Father, we lift
up the circumstances. We lift up your
people before you today. Have mercy, oh
God. Pull us out of the snare of the
fowler, Lord. The the the perilous
pestilence that come to destroy your
people, that come against your people,
Father, for we stand in you. Yet
believing have faith, Lord, having faith
only in you, who we know, God, that
there is nothing too hard for you,
Father. We're praying strengthen your
people today. Lift them up today, God.
Hold them, Lord. Hold them tight to your
uh to your uh unchanging hand, Lord, in
your bleeding side. May they feel your
your your your presence. May they feel
that peace that surpasses understanding.
Oh God, may they experience you in a
whole new realm today. That they've
never experienced you before, that their
faith will be increased. And Lord, that
your glory and your power will be
revealed here on earth. Father, we love
you. We praise you. We thank you. And we
glorify Lord your magnificent wonderful
name. Loving Father and we lift up our
pastor before you. Yes. Go before him oh
God and make the crooked path straight.
Father prepare the way Lord for the
message to come forth. I pray that every
heart be softened. I pray God that every
ear be attentive oh God to what the
spirit has to say to the church. Father
I pray that your hand of protection is
upon him. I pray that your hand of
guidance, your hand of mercy, your hands
of anointing oh God is upon him leading,
guiding God with your divine wisdom and
understanding. Infuse his mind oh God
with your holy spirit that the words
that come forth God words from heaven.
Father let the mana rain it down upon
your people oh God. Rain down fresh mana
from heaven upon the hearts Lord upon
the minds. We want to hear from heaven
today. What do you have to say, Lord?
What do you have to say to your church,
to your people? Let the spirit go forth
in our eyes, oh God, that everyone that
hear, let them hear what the spirit,
Lord, has to say to the church today.
Father, we thank you for all that you're
doing, for what you're continuing to do
in our lives. And Lord, we love you and
we praise you and we stand in your
presence, girded up in you and just
saying, "Father, rain down from heaven
on us today." Yes.
>> I pray this in the matchless magnificent
name of your son and our Lord and Savior
Jesus Christ. Amen. And amen.
>> Amen. Amen. May God's peace, power, and
presence rest upon you forever. Yes. And
ever
>> and ever.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. And amen. Praise God.
[Music]
I've heard a thousand
stories about
what they think you're like, but I've
heard the tender whispers love
the dead of night. And you tell me
that you're pleased and that I'm
never alone.
You're a good, good father. It's who you
are.
It's who you are.
It's who you are. And I'm loved by you.
It's who I am.
I've seen
many searching for answers
[Music]
far and wide. But I know
we're all searching for answers.
Only you provide. Cuz you know just what
we need before we
say a word.
You're a good father. It's who you are.
It's who you are.
who you are and I'm loved by you. That's
who I am.
So I am
You are perfect in all of your ways.
You are perfect.
Jesus,
you are perfect, Lord.
Oh.
[Music]
You're a good good father. It's who you
are.
It's who you are.
It's who you are. And I'm loved by you.
It's who I am. It's who I am.
who I am.
You are perfect in all of your ways,
Jesus.
You are
perfect.
perfect
in all of your ways,
Lord.
Oh,
you're a good good father. It's who you
are.
It's who you are.
It's who you are. And I'm loved by you.
It's who I am.
Who I am.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
[Applause]
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Hopefully hopefully we're going to have
our slides
up and ready. So y'all put one in the
chat if you can hear me.
All right.
volume is very low.
Testing one, two, testing one, two.
So, the audio is on, but it's
All right. Test one, two. Test one, two.
Testing one, two.
All right, now you can hear me with an
echo.
All right, I'm going to keep testing
till till y'all say you could hear me.
Hear me well. Testing, testing, testing.
One, two, one, two, one, two. All right.
Are we good?
There we go.
All right. Excellent. Excellent. So
guys, let's uh let's go ahead have a
word of prayer and we're going to jump
into today's message which which is
entitled The Man of Sin. the man of sin.
Uh let's pray. Heavenly Father, um we
come before you today, Lord, just asking
that you would take care of any
technical difficulties that we might be
having. Lord, I ask that you would
please speak through me, Lord. Um I pray
that the words that are shared today
will have a profound impact upon those
that are listening now and that will
listen in the future. We pray this in
Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
All right. Um,
we are going to
you guys are not going to be able to see
the slides, but I'm going to ask my team
if they can just have the slides uh
visible on my computer. Um, I will make
these slides available. Um,
but we are having some issues with the
slides. So,
uh, if I can just get my screen
uh cleared.
so I can see my slides. That would be
good. Um, as they're working on that,
I'm going to go ahead and begin. Um,
the man of sin. The man of sin. In 2
Thessalonians chapter 2:es 1-4, the
Bible says, "Now we beseech you,
brethren, by the coming of our Lord
Jesus Christ, and by our gathering
together unto him, that you be not soon
shaken in mind, or be troubled, neither
by spirit,
nor by word, nor by letter, as from us,
as that the day of Christ is at hand.
Let no man deceive you uh by any means,
for that day shall not come except there
come a falling away first and that man
of sin be revealed, the son of
predition, who opposes and exaltth
himself above all that is called God or
that is worshiped, so that he as God
siteth in the temple of God, showing
himself that he is God.
We understand that
at the very end of time, just before the
second coming of Christ,
um the man of sin
will make his final appearance. For
those of you that have watched my
messages before, you will understand
that the man of sin is ultimately Satan
himself.
And we're told that the day of the Lord
will not come except the man of sin
first appears. So we know that Satan
appears first and then uh Jesus comes at
the second coming.
We're also told that uh if it were
possible even the very elect would be
deceived. In Matthew chapter 24
beginning with verse 24, the Bible says,
"For there shall arise false Christ and
false prophets and shall show great
signs and wonders in so much that if it
were possible, they shall deceive the
very elect. We understand that Satan is
going to come at the end of time uh
pretending to be Christ." This is very
important to understand. Some people
will be deceived
simply because of false doctrine.
Simply because of false doctrine. Uh
Jesus carries on. He says uh in Matthew
24 uh wherefore if they shall say unto
you, behold he's in the desert, go not
forth. Behold, he's in the secret
chambers, believe it not. For as
lightning cometh out of the east, and
shineth even unto the west, so shall
also the coming of the Son of Man be.
Some people will be deceived by Satan
himself impersonating Christ
just through false doctrine.
Um, a failure to know what the Bible
says about the second coming of Christ.
um about the manner of his coming.
That's going to lead some people to be
deceived.
But that is not our focus today. Our
focus today is not to talk about why
those who are uh who are not biblically
grounded are going to be deceived. I
want to talk about those who may know
the Bible and may understand
um the the the the truths of the end
time. Um and by the way, I see in the
chat the challenges with the word man of
sin. Is Satan a man? No, Satan is not a
man. But when he comes, he is coming as
a man. He is coming as the man, Jesus
Christ. And so ultimately the ultimate
man of sin will be a demon appearing as
a man
as the divine son of God.
So
the question then becomes what is it
that will lead others who maybe know the
Bible
to accept this man of sin anyway.
That is a very serious question and I
want you to put a one in the chat if you
think that question is pretty relevant.
If it has you maybe even wondering about
yourself, man, what
what would lead me what would lead me to
actually
receive
and believe this counterfeit Jesus? Now,
some people getting in the chat are
asking, "Hey, isn't isn't the man of sin
according to, you know, according to the
Bible and according to many of the
Protestants? Isn't the man of sin the
papacy?" And the answer is yes. But the
papacy is not the ultimate man of sin.
We're going to be talking about that in
this message today. But as you may have
heard me say before, if you haven't
heard me say before, let me say it this
way. The papacy is to Satan what John
the Baptist was to Jesus. John the
Baptist only prepared the way
for Jesus. And in the same way, the
little horn of Daniel 7, which we will
look at in in not in detail today, but
the little horn of Daniel 7
is the one that comes before that is
preparing the way for the ultimate
manifestation of the man of sin.
So with that in mind, what we need to
understand in second Thessalonians is is
uh is actually talking about Satan
himself
sitting in the temple of God showing
himself that he is God. That is the
ultimate manifestation of the man of sin
at the end of time. Now
what we need to understand is that this
has been Satan's desire from the very
beginning. I want you to note with me
Isaiah 14:12 where the Bible says, "How
art thou fallen from heaven, oh Lucifer,
son of the morning, how art thou cut
down to the ground which did weaken the
nations? For thou hast said in thine
heart, I will ascend into heaven. I will
exalt my throne above the stars of God.
I will sit also on the mount of the
congregation
in the sides of the north. I will ascend
above the heights of the clouds. I will
be like the most high. I want you to
focus here on this on I want you to lock
in on that phrase, the mount of the
congregation in the sides of the north.
In Isaiah,
we have a description of Satan basically
saying, "I want to sit in the place of
God." Which parallels second
Thessalonians,
pointing to what will happen at the end
of time. What Satan wanted to do in
heaven, he's going to do on earth. What
is the sides of the north? What are the
sides of the north where this mount of
the congregation is? Let me share with
you. If you were to go to the Old
Testament sanctuary, you will notice in
in the book of Exodus chapter 26:35
where the Bible is going to tell us
about an article of furniture that is
located. Let me read. Thou shalt set the
table, that is the table of showbread,
without the veil, and the candlestick
over against the table on the side of
the tabernacle toward the south. and
thou shalt put the table on the north.
The table of showbread was located on
the sides of the north. The table of
showbread had 12 loaves of bread on it,
which in part was symbolic of the
congregation of Israel, the 12 tribes of
Israel. And so as we put this together
in heaven, Lucifer wanted to have
dominion
over the congregation in heaven.
And so he desired to have dominion over
God's congregation on earth in the Old
Testament, the 12 tribes of Israel. In
the New Testament, the church.
Are we good so far?
I want you to notice something else. In
Luke 4:4, the Bible says, "Jesus
answered him, saying, "It is written
that man shall not live by bread alone,
but by every word of God." The table of
showbread is symbolic of the word of
God. Meaning then, beloved, when we put
this all together, Satan sitting in the
temple is synonymous with him
leading the people and having the people
trust in his word over God's word.
Everybody put a five in the chat if that
makes sense so far.
The size of the north in the temple of
God in the sanctuary is where the table
of showbread was located. The table of
showbread is symbolic of the word of
God. Satan wants to have authority. He
wants his word to be as God's word. He
wants us to obey him as if we are
obeying God. Are y'all with me so far?
So, we understand then
that this has always been Satan's
desire. He wants God's word. He wants
his word rather I should say over God's
word. his word over God's word. I want
you to notice Genesis chapter 3 verse
one where the Bible says, "Now the
serpent was more subtle than any beast
of the field which the Lord God had
made. And he said unto the woman, "Yay,
has God said, you shall not eat of every
tree of the garden."
And the woman said unto the serpent, "We
may eat of the fruit of the we may eat
of the fruit of the trees of the garden,
but of the fruit of the tree which is in
the midst of the garden. God has said,
you shall not eat of it, neither shall
you touch it, lest you die."
And the serpent said unto the woman,
"You shall not surely die." I want you
to understand that even here in the
garden, Lucifer's goal, Satan's goal was
to have his word obeyed as the word of
God. His word obeyed over the word of
God. And so, I want to build on this
theme. I want to build on this idea of
Satan uh wanting to sit in the temple of
God. And to do that at the end of time,
to do that, we need to go back to the
temple of God at the beginning. And so
you'll remember
in the book of Exodus chapter 25:8
when God is introducing the temple or
the sanctuary to his people, he says,
"Let them make me a sanctuary that I may
dwell among them." And thus we
understand that the purpose of the
sanctuary was for God to dwell with his
people. It was for God to dwell amongst
his people. And so we can then
understand that if Satan wants to enter
into that sanctuary, it is for the
purpose of separating God from his
people, separating us from God. That is
his ultimate goal in wanting to sit in
God's place. In fact, we see the result
of of of Satan leading people to go
against God's will. We see this result
in Ezekiel 8:6 where the Bible says, "He
said further unto me, son of man, seeest
what thou what they do. Even the great
abominations of the house of Israel
committh here, or that the house of
Israel committeth here, that I should go
a far off from my sanctuary." So, I want
you to notice what happened when when
the temple was filled with abominations.
When the when the people were filled
with abominations, the end result was
that God would go far off far away from
his temple. And so, we see that Satan's
goal is to is that very thing. How can I
get God and the people separated?
Because if I can come in between God and
the people, then the people are mine.
The people are mine. And so again, we
read in Psalm 7 verse4 74:3-7,
the Bible says, "Lift up thy feet unto
the perpetual desolations, even all that
the enemy has done wickedly in the
sanctuary. Thine enemies roar in the
midst of thy congregation. They set up
end signs for signs." In other words, uh
uh God is demonstrating here. God is
showing us here how Satan's ultimate
goal is to destroy, is to is to do
wickedly in the sanctuary. And so we see
that the children of Israel in the Old
Testament
rebelled against God over and over and
over as a result of this rebellion. We
will see in 2 Kings chap 25 verse 8 and
9 that the sanctuary, the temple was
actually destroyed. The Bible says in
the fifth month and on the seventh day
of the month which is the 19th year of
King Nebuchadnezzar, king of Babylon,
came Nebu Nebuchad Zareden, captain of
the guard, a servant of the king of
Babylon unto Jerusalem. And he burnt the
house of the Lord and the king's house,
and all the houses of Jerusalem, and
every great man's house burnt he with
fire. We see the same thing in 2
Chronicles 36:18 and 19. all the vessels
of the house of God, great and small,
and the treasures of the house of the
Lord, and the treasures of the king, and
of his princes. All these he brought to
Babylon, and they burnt the house of
God, and break down the wall of
Jerusalem, and burnt the palace thereof
with fire, and destroyed all the goodly
vessels thereof. And so, we see we see
this this history of the temple being
destroyed. And it is ultimately Satan
who led in that. It is Satan who led the
people to so desecrate themselves
that the end result was the destruction
of the temple. The devil has has want
the devil has always wanted to either
destroy the temple or to sit in the
temple. If y'all with me so far, just
put a one in the chat. Put a one in the
chat. Pastor, we're following. We got
you. We're tracking.
And so we know that the temple is
ultimately rebuilt. The children of
Israel leave Babylon. The temple is
rebuilt. And when they rebuild the
temple, the people are are very sad
because the rebuilt temple doesn't look
anything like the first temple. A and
this is where in the book of Hagi
chapter 2:9, we're told that the
children of Israel were given a promise.
And here was a promise. The glory of
this latter house. Hagi 2:9 The glory of
this latter house
shall be greater than of the former say
the Lord of hosts and in this place will
I give peace saith the Lord of hosts.
How was this fulfilled
beloved? It was fulfilled
when Jesus himself
enters the temple
in Luke 4:16. The Bible says, "And as he
came to came to to Nazareth and as had
been as ad had been brought up where he
had been brought up, I'm sorry. And as
his custom was, he went into the
synagogue on the Sabbath day and stood
up for to read. And there was delivered
unto him the book of the prophet Isaiah.
And when he had opened the book, he
found the place wherein it was written,
uh, the spirit of the Lord is upon me
because he's anointed me to preach the
gospel to the poor. He has sent me to
heal the brokenhearted, to to preach the
divine to preach deliverance to the
captives and recovering of sight to the
blind, to set at liberty them that are
bruised, to preach the acceptable year
of the Lord. And it is so when Jesus
begins his ministry,
uh Jesus presence is going to grace that
temple throughout the three and a half
years of his ministry. And this is why
the glory of God surpassed the glory of
the temple
of the latter temple surpassed the glory
of the first temple. The glory of the
temple that they had built originally
because now Jesus
was in the very midst of them.
However,
the children of Israel rejected Jesus.
You'll see in Matthew 23:37 and 38, the
Bible says, "Oh Jerusalem, Jerusalem,
thou that klest the prophets," this is
Jesus speaking, "and stoned them which
are sent unto thee. How often would I
have gathered thy children together,
even as a hen gathered her chickens
under her wings, and ye would not behold
your house is left unto you desolate."
This was Jesus letting them know that
their temple was going to be destroyed.
and it was destroyed in 70 AD. In fact,
Jesus in the very next chapter, Matthew
24:1 and2, the Bible says Jesus went out
and departed from the temple, and his
disciples came to him for to show him
the buildings of the temple. And Jesus
said unto them, see not all these
things, verily I say unto you, there
shall not be left here one stone upon
another that shall not be thrown down.
Now guys, I've done a lot of building
here and I'm about to come to the main
point of this entire message.
The reason the temple was destroyed
was very significant.
It happened right before the death of
Jesus.
Jesus is brought before Pilate. Now, I'm
just going to read it to you. Let's go
to Matthew 27:15.
And beloved, this has everything to do
with why some people who know the truth
will end up receiving the man of sin at
the end of time. In Matthew 27:15, the
Bible says, "Now at the feast, the
governor was want to release unto the
people a prisoner whom they would. And
they had a notable prisoner called
Barabus. Barabus means bar, son of Abba
the father. Some transcripts actually
call his name Jesus Barabus.
Therefore, when they were gathered
together, Pilate said unto them, whom
will ye that I release unto you, Barabus
or Jesus, which is called the Christ?
For he knew that for envy they had
delivered him. When he was set down on
the judgment seat, his wife s unto him,
saying, "Have nothing to do with that
just man, for I have suffered many
things this day in a dream because of
him." But the chief priests and elders
persuaded the multitude that they should
ask for Barabus
and destroy
Jesus.
All right.
Why was the temple destroyed? Yes,
Nerky. because they accepted a
counterfeit Jesus.
They accepted a counterfeit Jesus, a
counterfeit son of the father.
This is absolutely significant.
So, let's pause right there for a
moment. And we know that in the in the
book of Daniel,
we read about these four these four
beasts, lion, bear, leopard, then the
fourth beast having 10 horns, and then a
little horn rises among this these 10
horns. And we read about that little
horn in Daniel 7:25,
saying, "He shall speak great words
against the most high, and shall wear
out the saints of the most high, and
think to change times and laws, and they
shall be given into his hand until a
time, times, and dividing of time." This
we know is the history of the papal
power, the history of the papacy during
the dark ages.
Now, now uh this same power is described
in Daniel 11 and verse 31.
And here you guys is our foundational
text.
Daniel 11:31, the Bible says, "And arm
shall stand on his part, and they shall
pollute the sanctuary of strength, and
shall take away the daily sacrifice, and
they shall place the abomination that
maketh desolate." I want you to notice
four things about this verse. Number
one, arms shall stand on his part.
Number two, they shall pollute the
sanctuary of strength. Number three,
they shall take away the daily. And
number four, they shall place the
abomination that maketh desolate.
You'll remember that Jesus put this text
in the future. He said, "When you shall
therefore see the abomination of
desolation spoken of by Daniel the
prophet, stand in the holy place, in the
temple, as it were, who so readeth, let
him understand." He continues on in
verse 21. For then shall be great
tribulations such as was not since the
beginning of the world, no, nor ever
shall be, and except those days should
be shortened, there shall no flesh be
saved, but for the elect's sake, those
days shall be shall be shortened. All
right,
you guys.
Not only did this happen in the past
during the dark ages,
the abominence of desolation,
but it is going to happen on a larger
scale in the future. This is the this is
what second Thessalonians is talking
about. The man of sin sitting in the
temple of God.
Now, there's something I need you to
understand, guys, because you've been
thinking one level all this time. You've
been thinking one level all this time.
But I need you to understand something.
When we when we understand that the man
of sin wants to come in and sit in the
temple of God, there is something that
we miss, you guys. There is something
that we miss.
And here it is. We know that Jesus is
coming again the second time. Amen. He's
coming again again the second time. He's
coming a second time. And those who
receive him at his coming must have
first received his spirit. Put a one in
the chat if that makes sense.
Only by receiving his spirit.
In other words,
only as Jesus's spirit is dwelling in us
now
will we be prepared
for when he literally comes again the
second time. Meaning he must come into
us now to prepare us to receive him when
he comes again the second time.
And it is significant, beloved, that his
spirit must dwell in us because because
watch this in 1 Corinthians 3:17 the
Bible says, "Know you not that you
are the temple of God, and that the
spirit of God dwelleth in you.
If any man defile the temple of God, him
will God destroy. for the temple of God
is holy which you are. So then watch
this then guys.
Jesus
is desiring
to sit in the temple of God.
And the reason he wants to sit in the
temple of God is to prepare these
temples to receive him when he comes
again the second time.
That's why that's why on the day of
Pentecost, Acts chapter 2:1, when the
day of Pentecost was fully come, they
were all with one accord in one place.
And suddenly there came a sound from
heaven as of a rushing mighty wind, and
it filled all the house where they were
sitting. And they were all, and there
appeared unto them cloven tongues like
as a fire, and it sat upon each of them,
and they were all filled with the Holy
Ghost, and began to speak with other
tongues, as the Spirit gave them
utterance. All right. So now I want you
to catch catch what's happening here. In
order for us to be to be ready and
accept Jesus at the second coming, we
must first have his spirit dwelling in
the temple. He dwells in the temple in
order to prepare these temples for his
second coming. Well, beloved, if that's
the case,
if that is the case,
and if we also know that Satan
will counterfeit the second coming of
Christ before the second coming of
Christ, in other words, as we just read
in 2 Thessalonians, we read earlier
chapter 2 verse one. Let me read it
again. Now we beseech you, brethren, by
the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, and
by our gathering together unto him, that
you be not soon shaken in mind, or
troubled, neither by spirit, nor by
word, nor by letter, ask from us, that
the day of the Lord is at hand. Let no
man deceive you by any means, for that
day shall not come, except there come a
falling away first. and the man of sin
be revealed who opposes and exaltth
himself above all that is called God or
that is worshiped so that he as God sits
in the temple of God showing himself
that he is God. Let me ask you a
question.
If Satan will come before Jesus comes
and will pretend to be Christ, is it not
then also clear that in order to prepare
a people to receive him, he must send
his spirit
into
the temples
that will receive him.
Let me let me ask the question again.
If Satan is coming before Christ,
counterfeiting Christ, if if if those
who receive Christ only receive him
because they had his spirit in them. In
other words, he was spiritually sitting
in the temple before he literally comes
again at the second time. And it is
because he's spiritually in the temple
that when we see Jesus we'll be like yes
that's him. Could it be possible then?
Not possible. Probable then. Not even
probable. Necessary
that before Satan comes appearing as
Jesus
that he would have first had to put his
spirit
in the temples
to lead them to the point that when they
see him, they'll be like, "Yes, that's
Jesus."
Wow.
So, you mean that the man of sin is
trying to sit in the temple
now?
That's right, y'all. The man of sin is
seeking to sit in your temple now. And
every time we read that verse, we
separate. We think about the end of
time. The end of time, the end of time.
I I'll know when Jesus come, his feet
don't touch the ground. But let me tell
you, if the spirit of Satan is already
in your temple, when Satan comes again,
100%.
You're going to be like, "That's him.
That's Jesus
100%."
So now we got to understand this. Okay.
All right. I get that, pastor. How can I
know? How can I make sure that sa what
would how will Satan seek to sit in the
temple to defile the temple? And the
answer goes back beloved the answer goes
back to Daniel 11:31.
I want you to watch how Satan operates
by watching how he operated in the
little horn in the in the past. Listen
to this. The first thing Daniel 11:31
and arms shall stand on his part. Arms
shall stand on his part. Let me just
simply say it this way.
Arms standing on the part of the little
horn back in the time back in the dark
ages was simply this. They had a
military. They had military force. Force
mark. They had military force behind
them to establish
righteousness.
If
a spirit
dwells with within you
that in any way says
it is okay to use force to establish
righteousness
in others.
You're operating
on the same principle of the little
horn. You're operating on the same
principle of the man of sin. In other
words, the man of sin has already found
a place in the temple
because God is not a God of force.
And if in our minds
we think that force is a good way to
establish
righteousness.
We are already entertaining the spirit
that is going to prepare us to receive
the man of sin when he actually comes in
the flesh.
See,
Revelation 13:16 says, "He causeth all,
both small and great, rich and poor,
free and bond, to receive a mark in
their right hand or in their forehead."
This is
forced
righteousness.
Forced righteousness. Let me go back one
verse.
Remember where it said uh in the same
verse Daniel 11:31 they shall pollute
the sanctuary of strength or they shall
arm shall stand on his part and they
shall pollute the sanctuary of strength.
What does it mean to pollute the
sanctuary of strength? Well, first of
all, what's a sanctuary of strength?
Well, it's God's sanctuary. And he calls
it the sanctuary of strength.
But how do you pollute the sanctuary of
strength? How does that happen?
We are supposed to be the sanctuary of
strength. How do you pollute that? You
pollute the sanctuary of strength when
you depend upon a strength outside of
God for righteousness.
Listen
here is God's strength. Zechariah 4:6.
Then he answered and spake unto me,
saying, This is the word of the Lord
unto unto Zerubbabel, saying, Not by
might, nor by power, but by my spirit,
sayeth the Lord of hosts.
God's strength is through his spirit.
Satan's strength is through force. And
anywhere you see Christianity
using force, know that this is the man
of sin operating.
Beloved, even even
amongst ourselves,
you can have there are people who have
the spirit of force among them. How can
I enforce righteousness in your life so
that you live the way that I want you to
live?
And we will do all kinds of things
except using the spirit to try to force
people to do right. Force people to live
right. Force people to to to to uh to to
to to follow to follow the way that we
would do things. Force. If I can't force
you by telling you to do this, I'm going
to force you through embarrassment. I'm
going to force you by calling you out.
I'm going to force you in every possible
way that I can think of because I love
you.
Force
is of Satan.
And anytime we implement force
to establish righteousness
to demand that other people should do
right and and whatever we need to do to
enforce them doing right that's what you
understand this is where things are
headed at the end of time the Christian
world will resort to force.
Now listen beloved there are things that
that you know
force is is required.
Absolutely force is not always a bad
thing. But when it comes to
righteousness
force is of Satan.
That's on a global scale and it's on a
personal scale. Some of us are so
concerned with what everybody else is
doing around us
because oh, you're not doing what I'm
doing. You're not living how you're not
you're not doing the right thing the
right way. That
we resort
to manipulative methods
in order to bring about righteousness.
Notice what else this this this power
does in Daniel 11:31. So we already saw
they shall pollute the sanctuary of
strength. We already saw arms shall be
on their part. And now I want you to
notice this. I want you to notice this.
Um Daniel 11:31 says again, "And shall
take away the daily sacrifice."
Shall take away the This is all in
Daniel 11:31. Now
that word sacrifice, that word sacrifice
is italicized meaning that it is not in
the text and the text is a little bit
misleading because it appears as as if
the text is saying uh that the daily
sacrifice pointing to the cross of
Christ is going to be taken away
which in a sense yes but it is so much
more than this. It is so much more than
this.
The word daily there is the Hebrew word
tamid.
And I'm going to show you that this word
is used very often in the temp regarding
the temple, regarding the sanctuary.
Listen, listen, listen.
Watch this.
In Exodus 29:38, the Bible says, "Now
this is that which thou shalt offer upon
the altar two lambs of the first year
day by day continually." That's the word
tamid. The altar of sacrifice was
considered a tamid was considered a
continual service. So when the Bible
says that this power, this man of sin
power will seek to take away the tamid,
it has something to do with the altar of
sacrifice. It also has something to do
with the seven branch candlestick. Thou
shalt command the children of Israel
that they bring the pure o olive beaten
for the light to cause the lamp to burn
always. Tamid
Tamid always
always
the altar of incense. Exodus 30:7 Aaron
shall burn thereon sweet incense every
morning. When he d when he dresseth the
lamps thereof, he shall burn incense
upon it. And when Aaron lightth the
lamps at evening, he shall burn incense
upon it, a perpetual tamid incense
before the Lord throughout your
generations. So the tamid was the altar
of incense. It was the candlestick. It
was the altar of sacrifice. And listen
to me, the table of showbread.
Exodus 24:5 through8 uh um after it
describes the table of showbread, it
says, "Every Sabbath he shall set it in
order before the Lord continually."
Tamid continually.
So then watch this.
What the man of sin does is he attacks
the table of showbread, the altar of
sacrifice, the seven branch candlestick,
and the altar of incense.
He destroys these things in the temple
in an attempt to defile the temple to
prepare the way for him to dwell in the
temple.
He's going to do something to alter
these articles of fer furniture and the
things that they represent. So then so
then if we took these one by one, listen
to me now.
If the to table of showbread represents
the the word of God. Are y'all with me?
The table of showbread represents the
word of God.
However,
however,
we can have the truth, the word of God,
and still have no love for the truth.
Let me say that again.
We can have the word of God, the table
of the the the table of showbread and
you know incense, frankincense was to be
placed upon the bread. We can have the
word of God and not have that sweet
incense. Not have that sweetness about
us. Yes, I believe in the truth. Yes, I
believe in the truth. Yes, sir. Yes,
sir. Yes, sir. We can have the word of
God and watch this. what may be termed a
jealous regard for truth
and still not be lovable, loving, kind,
patient,
merciful.
Wow.
So you mean I can still be eating the
word of God
and yet if I don't have love and mercy
and compassion and kindness
that in fact Satan can find a way into
my heart. Watch this. Now
remember, Satan doesn't come in saying,
"Hey guys, I'm Satan." He comes in
saying, "Hey, I'm Jesus." Could
it be possible that many of us are
walking around thinking that Jesus is
sitting in the temple when
it is in fact not the real or the right
Jesus.
The person who's in there says, "Yes,
I'm Jesus."
But it is not the right Jesus.
Just as when at the end of time when
this same individual comes in the flesh
and says, "I'm Jesus." If you were
deceived here about the Jesus that was
here, you will be not might, not
perhaps, you will be deceived by the
counterfeit Jesus if you are walking
around with a counterfeit Jesus. Now,
you see, the altar of sacrifice
represented self-sacrificing love. If
you claim to have Jesus, but you don't
have self-sacrificing love, you're not
willing to lay your life. You're not
willing. When Jesus was on the cross and
he said, "Father, forgive them for they
know not what they do." When Jesus wiped
away the people's sins and wrote the
people's sins in the sand, but wrote it
in a sand so that others couldn't see
it. If you are not of the mindset
where your love is so strong for others
and even your enemies that you're
willing to say, "Father, forgive them.
They know not what they do." If you
don't have that Jesus, but you still
claim that there's a Jesus in you, I'm
letting you know the spirit that is
within you is preparing you for that
last day spirit that is to come, which
is a counterfeit of Jesus.
If you cannot discern the counterfeit
Jesus in you now, you will not be able
to discern the counterfeit Jesus when he
comes in reality.
Many of us have a Jesus
dwelling in us
that knows the word of God, can quote
the word of God, and yet have no
compassion.
A Jesus who who prays
altar of incense
prays
for opportunity to exalt yourself above
others.
praise,
unrighteous prayers,
self-righteous prayers.
Lord, I'm I'm not like them. Those
people over there and those people over
there, thank you, Lord, that I'm not
like them.
No love. You have love for the people
you know for your friends but don't have
love for those you don't know and are
willing to treat those you don't know on
a whole different level than you be you
would treat those that you do know.
And what I want you to know is that the
Bible says he who turns away his ear
from the hearing of the law even his
prayer is an abomination.
I need you to understand if you cannot
discern a counterfeit Jesus
that might be dwelling in you right now,
a Jesus who lacks compassion,
a Jesus who desires force to make things
right in America and forced to make
things right, make other people do
right, we've got to st we must stand for
listen.
Yes, we must stand for the right. And we
do that through the preaching of the
gospel. We do that through praying for
the conversion of hearts. That is how
that is how we help society. That is how
we help people to stop living lifestyles
that are unlike uh what God wants. That
is how. And yet so many of us possess
this spirit of force of arms standing on
your part.
Arms.
And in doing this, beloved, what Satan
does is he he he counterfeits the table
of showbre. Oh man, you got the word of
God. That's right. He counterfeits the
altar of incense. Hey, you're praying.
He counterfeits the candlestick. Do not
think that in order to be a witness, you
have to there are certain things that
you must you must do and you must be and
and yes, if I do these things, but your
witness, your fire is really like the
fire of fanaticism
versus the fire of love.
Remember when Jesus's disciples said,
"Shall we call fire down upon our
enemies and consume them?" And Jesus
said, "You know not what you know what
not what manner of spirit you are of." I
need you to understand, beloved, that as
we read this text about the man of sin
sitting in the temple of God, I need you
to understand that the man of sin to a
great extent is already sitting in many
temples claiming to be Jesus, claiming
to be God. And and and because of the
lack of the spirit, we cannot discern
it. We think we have Jesus.
So, we see him attacking the the the
altar of sacrifice. We see him attacking
the the uh seven branch candlestick. We
see him attacking the table of
showbread. We see him attacking the
altar of incense. And beloved, all of
this we're thinking all of this I need
you to understand is
deception
deceiving the these temples that Jesus
is already in them when it is not Jesus
but that of another spirit.
And if you want to know how many people
who know the truth will end up receiving
Satan, it's because when they see him,
they will already be like he is
because that's who Satan is.
And it is a stunning thing that he could
pull off such great deception
right in the midst of the temples.
A a and and we remember in Daniel 7:25,
the same power uh uh changes times and
laws. Meaning, not only does he attack
the altar of sacrifice, not only does he
attack the altar of incense, not only
does he attack the table of show, not
only does he attack the table of
showbread, not only does he attack the
the seven branch candlestick and the
altar of he attacks the law of God.
And there are many many people who keep
the commandments and are and yet are not
keeping the commandments.
Yes.
It is another spirit. It is the spirit
of antichrist.
And beloved, the spirit of antichrist,
anti means in the place of Christ. Some
people think they have the Holy Spirit
when it is a spirit of another
of an antichrist.
The Bible tells us that love is the
fulfilling of the law.
There are many people who know the ten
commandments, know them in their correct
version,
and go to church on the right day of the
week,
who are not keeping the commandments.
Not keeping the commandments.
angry,
self-righteous,
um,
condemning.
We caught this woman in adultery,
that kind of a spirit.
All the while thinking
that it is Jesus in their temple
when in fact it is the man of sin in
their temple.
And so when the text says in Daniel
11:31 that he places the abomination
that maketh desolate, I need you to
understand that the abomination that
maketh desolate is Satan himself. It is
the spirit of antichrist in the dark
ages. It was the papacy.
At the end of time, it is the spirit of
Satan himself which will ultimately
prepare those who receive his spirit
to see this counterfeit Jesus and say,
"I know him.
I know him. This is the one that's been
dwelling in my heart.
And even though his feet touch the
ground,
your spirit
will be so caught up in the false glory.
And because you've had that spirit like
him, the spirit of force, the spirit of
self-righteousness, the spirit of
condemnation to others, that spirit,
that uh spirit, that's what I'm going to
call it, that uh spirit
under a disguise of righteousness and
truth.
the overwhelming glory that he comes
with is that last thing that just needs
to to it's it's that last thing that
that leads those to say this is Jesus.
This is Jesus.
It's a weird thing, guys, to watch to
watch things progress.
Um, and to see people now believing
something that they never believed
before, now acting in ways that they
never acted before. It's a strange
thing. We kind of see it happening all
around us. And it it's like the bar just
keeps getting lower and lower and lower.
And
there is a reason why Jesus says if it
were possible even the very elect would
be deceived. So the question is pastor h
how do I ensure how do I ensure that I
have the right Jesus in me? And um
I'm going to share with you
I'm going to share with you just just a
few more verses. Just a few more verses.
Psalm 51:7, the Bible says, "Purge me
with hissip and I shall be clean. Wash
me and I shall be whiter than snow."
I want you to keep that text in mind
because Jesus says, "Listen, I'll wash
you." Um, you may realize that you had
the wrong spirit in you. the spirit of
pride, the spirit of self-exaltation and
self-righteousness, the spirit of
condemnation, the spirit of force.
And God says, "Don't worry. I'm the I'm
the
I'm the one that is stronger than the
strong man.
I'm the one that's stronger than I can
come into you and cleanse you and get
the spirits out."
And we ought to say, "Praise God." We
also ought to know that those spirits
are always looking to come back. They're
always looking to come back. Psalm 51:7,
"Purge me with hissup and I shall be
clean. Wash me and I shall be white as
snow." Purge me of what? Purge me of the
false
Purge me from the false idea that I can
love truth and yet hate people. that I
can love truth. Let me say it this way.
That I can love truth because no one's
gonna say I hate people. No. Who hates
people? Nobody's gonna raise their hand.
You don't have to raise your hand
though. It's how you act. It's how you
treat. It's how it's all in the actions.
So many times these righteous actions
that we pull that we do
is a real demonstration of how little
love we have for one another.
Right?
So, I want you to notice this. I want
you to notice this in Isaiah chapter
6:1. Isaiah chapter 6 vers1, the Bible
says, "In the in the year that King
Uzziah died, I saw also the Lord sitting
upon a throne high and lifted up and his
train filled the temple." That's what I
want you to understand.
That's what I want you guys to
understand. His train literally me
literally means the hem of his garment.
Remember that story of the woman who
touched the hem of Jesus's garment and
she was healed.
She was healed the moment she touched
the garment is the garments of Christ's
righteousness.
And Isaiah says that his train his
garment his righteousness
filled the temple.
Now if something is filled then it's not
possible for other things to get in
there. There's no room here. You know
when you go into a place and it's
standing room only there's no space for
anybody else to come into. Right? Lord
help me
to allow you to fill
my temple. Watch this. First Kings
chapter 8 10 and 11. First Kings chapter
8 10 and 11. This is our closing verse
you guys. It came to pass when the
priests were come out of the holy place
that the cloud the cloud the cloud the
cloud that is the spirit of God. The
cloud filled the house of the Lord. So
that the priests could not stand to
minister because of the cloud. For the
glory of the Lord had filled the house
of the Lord. See those last words right
there. For the glory of the Lord had
filled the 12 words. I think it's 12
words. That right there is the gospel.
For the glory of the Lord had filled the
house of the Lord. You are the house of
the Lord.
And the devil, the man of sin, wants
access to your house.
Are you following me?
The only way that we can prevent him
from coming in is to be filled with the
spirit of God. What is that spirit?
Love, joy, peace, longsuffering,
gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness,
temperance.
Lord, fill me with your spirit.
If I claim
to keep the commandments of God, but I
do not have love, joy, peace,
gentleness, goodness, faith,
longsuffering, if I don't have those
things,
commit, you're not keeping the
commandments of God.
If you claim to know the truth, the
table of showbread, you know the word,
you know all the true doctrines, you got
it down. You can know all of that,
beloved. And if you do not have love,
not for those who you also, not for your
close friends, not for those in your
crew, but love for everyone,
including people who do not live like
you, act like you, look like you, talk
like you, believe like you.
If you don't have love for your enemies,
your perceived enemies, you may you may
be you may eat at the table of showbread
all day long. The word of God is not
dwelling in you.
You may pray to God, I pray every
morning. I pray at this time, at this
time, at this time, and I pray, pray,
pray, pray, pray. You can pray all day
long. And if you do not have the love of
God, love, joy, peace, longsuffering,
gentleness, goodness, faith me. If you
don't have those things in your temple,
there's another spirit in your temple.
Period.
Bottom line.
And listen, that spirit will lead you to
hear things that are not said.
For example, you're telling me that I
got to love, you know, the sin, the love
this person who's involved in the sin.
Yes, you have to love that person that
is involved in the sin. That doesn't
mean love the sin. That doesn't mean
excuse the sin, but nonetheless, you
have to love that person and do all in
your power to minister to that person,
not through force, but through love.
You may be passing out tracks all day
long.
All day long. I'm witnessing. I'm w I'm
letting my light shine.
But if your light isn't shining through
love, joy, peace, longsuffering,
gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness,
temperance. Your light is darkness. It's
strange fire. You may have zeal all day
long. I'll do this and I'll debate all
day long. If you don't have love, joy,
peace, longsuffering, gentleness,
goodness, faith, if you are not
exhibiting the nature of Christ, I
talked about this in Sabbath school. So
many arguments about what nature did
Christ have. It doesn't matter what
nature Christ had because Christ's
nature
was was perfect.
Christ's nature was righteous. Christ's
nature was holy. And instead of us
getting caught up in, well, what nature
did he have? Was it pre was it uh the
the pre-fall nature or postfall nature?
It doesn't matter. We need the nature of
Jesus. If you do not have the nature of
Jesus,
I'm just letting you know there's
another spirit dwelling in you. This
doesn't mean, listen to me y'all. This
doesn't mean that you that you never
ever sin. That's not what I've just
said. This doesn't mean that you can
never fall. This doesn't mean that you
can't, you know, make mistakes. None of
that. What I'm saying is if you're if
you are living a general flow of life in
which you are you you fail to exhibit
the fruit of the spirit, not the
occasional misdeed or the occasional
good deed. The flow of your life is
yeah, I got the word of God. Yeah, I'm
keeping the commandments. Yeah, I'm out
witnessing. And yeah, I pray. But you
got a nasty spirit. A spirit that
rejoices in other people's sins. A
spirit that rejoices when other people
fall. A spirit that rejoices when you
see other people doing things and you
lift yourself up and want to show
people, look how much better I am than
what they are. Look at what this
person's doing and look at what that
person's doing. Do you see the
wickedness?
That's another spirit.
It's another spirit, y'all.
It's another spirit.
So our prayer ought to be Lord fill me
with your spirit so that there is no
room the devil there's no place for the
devil to find footing.
fill me with your spirit
so that while I study, while I read the
word of God, while I'm keeping the
commandments, while I'm praying, while
I'm letting my light shine, help me,
Lord, help me to exhibit
genuine
kindness,
truth, mercy, longsuffering.
Help me Lord
because the fruit of the spirit combined
with all the articles of furnish in the
sanctuary that is what will keep you
from receiving the man of sin when he
comes in the flesh.
So today I'm making an appeal
and I want to ask you
I want to ask you this. Have you
have you identified
after hearing this message? Can you say,
you know what,
I'm not sure if the Jesus that's in me
is the right Jesus. Now listen y'all,
even if you were to say that, even if
you were to be like, man, I don't know.
I need you to understand that if Jesus
is not inside you, he's still outside
you knocking at the door.
He's still saying, "Hey, I would like to
come in." He's not forsaking you. He's
just saying, "Listen, you have someone
else on the inside."
But but pastor, I've been I've been I've
been a Christian for this long.
[Music]
You've had another spirit
for that long.
I've been chasing you for that long.
I mean, think of the Pharisees
who perhaps all their lives were brought
up believing in God
and not knowing that they had another
God in them.
That while they thought Abraham was
their father, it was actually Satan that
was their father. Don't think that that
cannot happen now.
And I'm telling you as I'm watching our
world today, it is becoming
it is become is it is a scary thing to
watch people now embrace
embrace coldness as an attribute of
Christianity.
Embrace mockery. embrace
uh just strong language that it's like
this boldness to say stuff that we
wouldn't wouldn't have said before.
We might think, "Oh, that's bold." You
know, we got to be bolden.
But I'm letting you know it is another
spirit.
It is not the spirit of Jesus.
So
today you're saying, "Lord,
I'm not even sure, but I need to be sure
that I have the right Jesus in me, the
right spirit in me. And I'm asking you
right now, Jesus,
to no longer let me take for granted
that I have that I have the right Jesus
in my temple. I need to know that. I
know that I know that I know. And the
way that I will know that I know that I
know that I know is if I have the fruit
of the spirit in me. So Lord, fill me
with your spirit. Fill me with your
presence. If that is your desire, I'm
going to ask you to put a one in the
chat. Put a one in the chat. In fact,
if that's your desired desire, I know I
can't see you, but wherever you are,
just stand up. Just say, "Yeah, Lord."
Stand up. If you're like, "Yeah, I know.
I know." Put a one in the chat if you
don't know. Stand up. If you're like,
"Yeah, that's me. My spirit's got to
change. I'm too easily angered. I'm too
easily f when Peter."
Remember, you know, not what manner of
spirit you are. I I'm I'm I condemn
people. I I I I look I
Lord, help me to get that spirit out of
me. Help me to get that spirit out of
me. So, some of you are standing.
Wherever you are, praise God for you
standing. Some of you are putting the
one in the chat. Praise God for you
putting that one in the chat. Lord, help
us. Whoever hears this word, help us to
know
that we have the son of man and not the
man of sin dwelling in our temples. So
that when the man of sin comes,
everything in our being will reject him.
because we know that that is not the
spirit of God and that when Jesus comes
everything in our spirit will connect
with him because he has already been
dwelling in the heart.
Let's pray. Heavenly Father, we thank
you Lord that you've shown us today
that while we are looking to the future
to see the ultimate fulfillment, the
ultimate fulfillment of the man of sin
seeking to stand in the place of God
pretending to be Jesus remind us that he
is doing that even now to prepare for
his final deception.
And Lord, remind us that if we do not
have Jesus dwelling in us, it's another
spirit.
And that spirit is preparing us to
receive the man of sin. Lord, help that
not to be the case for any of us. Lord,
help us to have you, the true Jesus,
with the true spirit dwell within our
hearts. Fill our temples. Let the train
of your glory fill our temple
so that no one can have access to this
temple but you God.
Thank you for hearing and for answering
this prayer because we ask it in Jesus
name. Be with everyone who's made a
decision today. Those who have those who
stood and those who simply put the one
in the chat. Minister to them Lord.
This is our prayer in Jesus name. Amen.
And amen.
We're going to go ahead and put the uh
link for the afterglow in the chat. Um
hope to see you all there. There. May
God bless you and keep you. For those of
you who are interested in Bible study,
I'm going to go ahead and let me see if
I can put this uh uh the slides up on
the screen to to either connect. You've
got a prayer request or if you want to
get involved in Bible studies for
baptisms, uh you will see it on the
screen. Uh there is uh the uh Bible
worker at living.urch.
That is an email um for those interested
in Bible study. And then we have several
uh QR codes that you could scan. Maybe
it's not going to go up on the screen.
We'll see.
All right. Um looks like it won't be up
on the screen, but uh we'll have this in
the link below the video once it's
posted to YouTube. Um and again, guys,
may God bless you and keep you. Um
and we will see you guys next week by
God's grace.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]